<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[Argena Wiki]]></title><description><![CDATA[Obsidian digital garden]]></description><link>http://wiki.alexsievert.com/</link><image><url>http://wiki.alexsievert.com/lib/media/favicon.png</url><title>Argena Wiki</title><link>http://wiki.alexsievert.com/</link></image><generator>Webpage HTML Export plugin for Obsidian</generator><lastBuildDate>Wed, 26 Mar 2025 02:19:53 GMT</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://wiki.alexsievert.com/lib/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><pubDate>Wed, 26 Mar 2025 02:19:46 GMT</pubDate><ttl>60</ttl><dc:creator/><item><title><![CDATA[The Helvalic Dominion]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br>The Helvalic Dominion occupied the land of Holfirth before the Larenthian Alliance took over in 1508 PS. The Helvalic people devoutly worshipped <a data-href="Valos" href="http://wiki.alexsievert.com/argena/gods/valos.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Valos</a>. They built the Solar Nexus south of the Eldermere Lake to try to communicate with <a data-href="Valos" href="http://wiki.alexsievert.com/argena/gods/valos.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Valos</a> and travel to Arborea. The Helvalic Dominion came to an end due to increasing pressure from the rising Larenthian Alliance invading from the east.]]></description><link>http://wiki.alexsievert.com/argena/chandaria/chandarian-history/helvalic-dominion-notes/the-helvalic-dominion.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Argena/Chandaria/Chandarian History/Helvalic Dominion Notes/The Helvalic Dominion.md</guid><pubDate>Sat, 10 Feb 2024 18:34:45 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Pylith]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br>In the ruins of Osmirith, devastated by the upper deities during the Great Dissension, a flourishing town of war-dispersed people began to take roots in 153 PS. The town thrived for its first few decades. The Westerwood's magic made the forest produce an extraordinary amount of resources, so Pylith grew rapidly. The town however, wouldn't survive forever.<br>When the Age of Dragons began, Pylith fell under the control of Drok Bonecrush, the hobgoblin warlord that controlled most of the Westerwood. Drok and his armies extorted the town for everything it was worth, until a group of unlikely heroes rose against him and freed the town.]]></description><link>http://wiki.alexsievert.com/argena/chandaria/chandarian-history/post-dissension/the-chandari-dark-ages/pylith.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Argena/Chandaria/Chandarian History/Post-Dissension/The Chandari Dark Ages/Pylith.md</guid><pubDate>Sun, 09 Jun 2024 20:41:20 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Ith Alora]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br>At the base of Mount Tayeche, the Westerwood was more of a jungle, and nestled inside the dense jungle was the elven city of Ith Alora. The elves that built the city didn't want to bother the natural beauty of the jungle, so half of the city was built among the treetops of the large jungle trees. At the time it was built, the city was an architectural marvel. Due to the lack of connections between the city-states, the building techniques didn't spread.<br>The modern capital city of Sella Alora is built over the ruins of the ground buildings of Ith Alora, which survived because of their superior construction.]]></description><link>http://wiki.alexsievert.com/argena/chandaria/chandarian-history/pre-dissension/ith-alora.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Argena/Chandaria/Chandarian History/Pre-Dissension/Ith Alora.md</guid><pubDate>Mon, 03 Jun 2024 23:15:19 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Mondrall]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br>Mondrall was a city-state on the Opulent Steppe during the Pre-Dissension era. It was a place dedicated to Genesis. Located right next to the Billowing Grove, a forest teeming with life and resources. Genesis visited the city-state often, and she made life there a veritable paradise. The city-state was mostly humans, but a few other fey creatures lived there as well.]]></description><link>http://wiki.alexsievert.com/argena/chandaria/chandarian-history/pre-dissension/mondrall.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Argena/Chandaria/Chandarian History/Pre-Dissension/Mondrall.md</guid><pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2025 20:29:23 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Monfort]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br>Situated on the slopes of Mount Tayeche (which is now known as the Exalted Summit), Monfort was one of the larger cities of the Pre-dissension time. It had no patron deity, instead relying on heavy fortifications and an extremely defensible position on the side of the mountain to keep it safe.<br>Due to it's lack of divine influence, Monfort actually survived the Great Dissension and stood as a bastion of civilization in the decades following the Scourge. However, the city was not safe from Anteitic ideologies, and it was a safehaven for early practitioners of the arcane arts. ]]></description><link>http://wiki.alexsievert.com/argena/chandaria/chandarian-history/pre-dissension/monfort.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Argena/Chandaria/Chandarian History/Pre-Dissension/Monfort.md</guid><pubDate>Mon, 03 Jun 2024 22:39:16 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Pre-Dissension Chandaria]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br>No one knows exactly how long Chandaria (and Argena as a whole) have been around. Recorded history only really goes back to the beginning of the Dissension. Many historians and archaeologists have made it their life goal to answer this question. They have found artifacts that likely date back to a little less than 10,000 BD (before dissension). So the common consensus is that Chandaria likely existed for at least 12,000 years before the Dissension. Basic facts are known about this pre-dissension world, but beyond that is all merely speculation.<br><br>It is common knowledge that wizardry and study of the arcane was a Dissension-era idea. Up to that point, the gods had done their very best to keep magic out of the hands of mortals. That being said, some creatures that walked the planes during the <a class="internal-link" data-href="Gods and Mythos.md" href="http://wiki.alexsievert.com/argena/gods-and-mythos.html" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Fracture</a> had raw magic infused into them. The classic example of this is the dragons, but there are many others besides them such as giants, fiends, and celestials.<br>
The gods were not happy that there were mortal creatures with access to magic, but they decided that it would be too disruptive to the multiverse to attempt to revoke that magic or to exterminate these creatures. Even enhanced by magic, these creatures were still nowhere near as powerful as the gods.<br><br>Many humanoid races trace their origins back to civilizations that existed pre-Dissension. During this time, Gods exerted much greater influence on the material plane than in the post-Scourge era. Most races lived in isolated city-states, leaving much of the world unexplored. Each city-state had a patron deity. Life was easy for them, the patron deity of each civilization would assist their constituents and provide them with the basic necessities.<br>
From an arcane technological perspective, these civilizations were barbaric, but in reality they were not uncivilized by any means. These city-states often had advanced forms of government, complex architecture, and ingenious clockwork devices.<br>
Despite the advanced nature of these civilizations, nearly all evidence of them was wiped from the annals of history during the Great Dissension.<br><br>Before the <a class="internal-link" data-href="The Great Dissension.md" href="http://wiki.alexsievert.com/argena/chandaria/chandarian-history/the-great-dissension.html" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Battle of the Planes</a>, the Central Chandaria was known as the Opulent Steppe. These fertile grasslands were home to many of the humanoid civilizations of the time. Green rolling hills stretched beyond the horizon in all directions and teemed with wildlife. It was a veritable paradise. This all changed when the <a class="internal-link" data-href="The Great Dissension.md" href="http://wiki.alexsievert.com/argena/chandaria/chandarian-history/the-great-dissension.html" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Battle of the Planes</a> permanently marred the landscape. The once lush land became an inhospitable waste. Flowing rivers dried up and became rocky canyons. Jagged mountains erupted from the ground during battle. Raging storms ravaged any and all lifeforms. Thus the Eternal Scorch was created, and will remain forever.]]></description><link>http://wiki.alexsievert.com/argena/chandaria/chandarian-history/pre-dissension/pre-dissension-chandaria.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Argena/Chandaria/Chandarian History/Pre-Dissension/Pre-Dissension Chandaria.md</guid><pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 02:57:18 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Pylaxes]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br>A great Elven hero from the Pre-Dissension era, Pylaxes secured his immortal legacy in through his union with Tiamat. <br><br>Pylaxes was one of the most well-traveled mortals of the Pre-Dissension era. He originally hailed from the Elvish city-state of Osmirith in the western forests of Chandaria, known as the <a data-href="Westerwood" href="http://wiki.alexsievert.com/argena/chandaria/chandarian-history/pre-dissension/westerwood.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Westerwood</a>. However, he was never satisfied with accepting life as it was, and he took to wandering as soon as he learned to wield a sword and ride a horse.<br>Initially, he explored just to see what was out in the world. Much of the continent was still completely unexplored, and he sought to expand his city's knowledge of the world. In his years of adventuring, he doubled Osmirith's claimed land, and even founded his own city-state known as Pylos.<br><br>North of Osmirith in the mountains near the present-day Exalted Summit, Pylaxes learned of a chimera that was terrorizing many of the peaceful woodland beings in the area. Armed with nothing but a shortsword, wooden shield, and chain shirt, Pylaxes climbed for four days up to the chimera's cave in the peaks. Showing great cunning, he snuck into the cave while the chimera was out hunting, and waited until it returned, then ambushed it in its sleep.<br>Pylaxes gained great favor with the neighboring forest creatures for slaying the chimera, and they helped him out on his future adventures. They blessed him with great knowledge of the surrounding area as well.<br><br>While establishing Pylos, Pylaxes and the initial settlers were struggling with an army of trolls that was invading from the south. These trolls were a prominent tribe known as the Ekleks, led by a mutated troll called Skug. They hailed from the coastal cliffs to the south. They had begun a campaign into the Westerwood, destroying the forest as they went.<br>Pylaxes sought to put an end to the Eklek's invasion of his new territory, so he devised a plan. Being heavily outnumbered and underpowered, he needed to be extremely cunning. Knowing the trolls' affinity for rotting corpses, Pylaxes gathered up all of the bodies from the most recent battle and piled them at the bottom of a hill. When the trolls came to feast, Skug insisted that he eat first. As soon as Skug approached the pile, Pylaxes lit a huge wooden ball covered in oil and pushed it down the hill. The flaming ball crashed through the ranks of trolls, killing many instantly, including Skug. The rest retreated and were never seen again.<br><br>Pylaxes's greatest adventure was his battle with the Ancient Blue Dragon Tienralt. Tienralt was the last thing holding back Pylos from becoming the most prosperous city-state in the whole region. Tienralt constantly collected tithes from Pylos and Osmirith, so Pylaxes decided to put an end to it.<br>
He gathered a party of the best adventurers he had met throughout his travels and set out towards Tienralt's Lair.<br>This time, Pylaxes didn't use any tricks. His party fought Tienralt head-on. They took heavy losses, losing three of the five members during the fight. This angered Pylaxes, who climbed the wing of the dragon and jumped from the top, driving his sword straight through the base of the dragons skull, killing it.<br><br>When Tiamat learned of the death of Tienralt, she was outraged, and went to investigate the region. She tracked Pylaxes back to Pylos and confronted him. In his last great heroic action, Pylaxes was somehow able to seduce Tiamat, and she left Pylos alone.<br>Despite Tiamat being bound to Gruumsh, she and Pylaxes had four children, who became <a data-href="The Great Serpents" href="http://wiki.alexsievert.com/argena/chandaria/chandarian-history/pre-dissension/the-great-serpents.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">The Great Serpents</a>.]]></description><link>http://wiki.alexsievert.com/argena/chandaria/chandarian-history/pre-dissension/pylaxes.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Argena/Chandaria/Chandarian History/Pre-Dissension/Pylaxes.md</guid><pubDate>Mon, 10 Feb 2025 02:19:07 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[The Great Serpents]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br>There were four Great Serpents that roamed the material plane during the <a class="internal-link" data-href="Pre-Dissension Chandaria" href="http://wiki.alexsievert.com/argena/chandaria/chandarian-history/pre-dissension/pre-dissension-chandaria.html" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Pre-Dissension</a> era. They were all children of <a data-href="Tiamat" href="http://wiki.alexsievert.com/argena/gods/tiamat.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Tiamat</a> and the mortal hero <a data-href="Pylaxes" href="http://wiki.alexsievert.com/argena/chandaria/chandarian-history/pre-dissension/pylaxes.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Pylaxes</a>. The Serpents were all bastard children, as <a data-href="Tiamat" href="http://wiki.alexsievert.com/argena/gods/tiamat.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Tiamat</a> was still bonded to <a data-href="Gruumsh" href="http://wiki.alexsievert.com/argena/gods/gruumsh.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Gruumsh</a> when she had the children with <a data-href="Pylaxes" href="http://wiki.alexsievert.com/argena/chandaria/chandarian-history/pre-dissension/pylaxes.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Pylaxes</a>. <a data-href="Gruumsh" href="http://wiki.alexsievert.com/argena/gods/gruumsh.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Gruumsh</a> despised these wedlock children so he cursed them. The Serpents, who initially resembled dragons, were stripped of their wings and appendages, turning them into essentially massive snakes. The Serpents then had children amongst themselves known as the Serpentkin. The Great Serpents and their children fought alongside <a data-href="Tiamat" href="http://wiki.alexsievert.com/argena/gods/tiamat.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Tiamat</a> during the <a class="internal-link" data-href="The Great Dissension.md" href="http://wiki.alexsievert.com/argena/chandaria/chandarian-history/the-great-dissension.html" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Great Dissension</a>.<br><br>Himmelslang was known as the Sky Serpent. He was the favorite serpent of <a data-href="Tiamat" href="http://wiki.alexsievert.com/argena/gods/tiamat.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Tiamat</a>, so she tried everything in her power to reverse the curse. Himmelslang ended up having a set of dragon wings grafted onto him and with this, he became the sky serpent.<br>
Himmelslang was said to encircle the entire sky, protecting Argena from extraplanar threats. His main battles were usually against invaders from the Astral Plane. Himmelslang's greatest battle was with an Elder Brain that was attempting to expand its empire into the material plane.<br><br>Haval is the Water Serpent. When she was cursed, she exiled herself to the Azure Expanse, taking to life beneath the waves, a place where most dragons stay far away from. She spent centuries swimming through the great blue depths of the Azure Expanse, emerging very rarely, and adapting to a life without air.<br>
Some Post-Scourge sailors claim to see Haval sometimes in the depths of the ocean. While these are simply tall tales, many of these sailors swear by their accounts.<br><br>Jordun and Svibrann were the other two of the great serpents. They were born twins and were constantly competing with each other. Jordun claimed <a data-href="Chandaria" href="http://wiki.alexsievert.com/argena/chandaria/chandaria.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Chandaria</a> do be his, while Svibrann claimed Enulon for herself. Some of the mountain ranges on these continents are rumored to be areas where these Serpents broke through the ground. At the same time, volcanoes are also said to be spots where the Serpents burst out, leaving behind fiery aftermath.<br>
Svibrann always made fun of Jordun for how much bigger her continent was than his. Jordun became self-conscious about <a data-href="Chandaria" href="http://wiki.alexsievert.com/argena/chandaria/chandaria.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Chandaria</a> and tried his best to make it as luxurious of a place as possible. He was constantly keeping the Serpentkin and other ambitious creatures in check. Because of this, he was called The Equalizer by some.<br><br>The Great Serpents and the Serpentkin fought alongside <a data-href="Tiamat" href="http://wiki.alexsievert.com/argena/gods/tiamat.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Tiamat</a> in the <a class="internal-link" data-href="The Great Dissnesion" href="http://wiki.alexsievert.com/The Great Dissnesion" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Great Dissension</a>. After the Scourge, it was decided that they would be sent to the Elemental Planes. Himmelslang was sent to the Plane of Air, Haval to the Plane of Water, Jordun to the Plane of Earth, and Svibrann to the Plane of Fire.<br>
Over time, the Serpents each developed abilities that fit with their respective planes. Svibrann regained her draconic fire breath, Haval because the quickest swimmer on the Plane of Water, and Himmelslang grew his own wings and became better at flying.<br>
Upon their assignment to the Elemental Planes, the Great Serpents were also given the tasks of protecting the Inner Planes by maintaining the border between the Elemental Planes and the Outer Planes. The Serpents became masters of the Elemental Chaos, able to traverse it with ease, patrolling for vagrants from the Outer Planes. ]]></description><link>http://wiki.alexsievert.com/argena/chandaria/chandarian-history/pre-dissension/the-great-serpents.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Argena/Chandaria/Chandarian History/Pre-Dissension/The Great Serpents.md</guid><pubDate>Mon, 03 Jun 2024 23:59:41 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Westerwood]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br>The Westerwood was the large forest that spanned most of the western coast of Chandaria in the Pre-Dissension era. It was home to many city-states of the time, the most notable of which was Pylos. The Westerwood was already ancient by the time of the Great Dissension, so many claimed that it was one of the first things on Chandaria to be created by the Gods. Due to the forest's age, many ancient creatures lived there. Treants, Dragons, and Giants all called it home.<br>The Westerwood was also said to have connections directly to the Gods. One species of tree found exclusively in this forest was known as Elderbark trees. These trees were massive, dominating the area where they grew. As such, they were pretty rare, as too many resources would be required to sustain two close to each other. It was said that the roots of these trees grew so deep that they reached all the way through the Interplanar Fabric and drew magical energy from the other planes.<br>The very few explorers that did venture beyond the walls of their city-states found areas of the Westerwood where creatures from other planes lived on the Material Plane. It was theorized that the Elderbark trees created a network of energy that opened gates to other planes. Some say that the explorers that never came back went through these gates and left their plane forever.<br>Parts of the Westerwood survive to this day, but most of it was deforested by mages during the Arcane Resurgence looking for ways to harness the energy of the Elderbark trees.]]></description><link>http://wiki.alexsievert.com/argena/chandaria/chandarian-history/pre-dissension/westerwood.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Argena/Chandaria/Chandarian History/Pre-Dissension/Westerwood.md</guid><pubDate>Mon, 03 Jun 2024 02:18:29 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[An Overall History Of Chandaria]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br>Chandaria has existed for as long as Argena, and is steeped in history, being the setting of many important historical events.<br><br>Time in Chandaria, and Argena as a whole, is measured in relation to the <a class="internal-link" data-href="The Great Dissension.md" href="http://wiki.alexsievert.com/argena/chandaria/chandarian-history/the-great-dissension.html" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Great Dissension</a>, since it is by far the most influential historical event in the world's history. Years are either Pre-Dissension (PD) or Post-Scourge (PS). 0 years Pre-Dissension is marked by the Initial Incursion. 0 years Post-Scourge is marked by the signing of the Abdication Accords. Between these two events is the Great Dissension, in which Argena was irrevocably changed.<br><br>Pre-Dissension Chandaria was a simplistically peaceful place. The humanoid races all lived in small city-states, each with a patron deity. Some deities, Genesis for example, were the patrons of multiple city-states.<br>The city-states all lived very independently of each other. Some communicated with each other but had no need to trade or travel at all. Pre-Dissension times are defined by heavy divine influence. Gods freely walked the material plane, and directly manipulated the world with their powers. They provided everything for their constituents, which generally kept the peace.<br>Beyond the reaches of these city-states roamed all manner of creatures. Most of the creatures survive to this day, but a few have became items of legend. The Great Serpents, demigods in their own right, held immense power over the material plane, but lost it during the Great Dissension.<br><br><a data-href="The Great Dissension" href="http://wiki.alexsievert.com/argena/chandaria/chandarian-history/the-great-dissension.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">The Great Dissension</a> irrevocably changed all of Argena. The conflict began as tensions between the Gods of the upper and lower planes grew to a head and lasted for 4 centuries. Nearly every race and creature was involved in the war in some way. Gods of both sides recruited mortals to fight on their side. Many modern religions can be traced back to these allegiances. <br>The gods taught a select few humanoids to harness the weave and use magic through arcane practice. Eventually, these people realized the true power that the Gods were keeping to themselves. They recognized that they could potentially harness the weave and kill the Gods, ending the war that had displaced or killed so many of their friends and families. The original wizards of both sides formed a secret alliance, known as the Anteity League, and themselves became known as the Ancient Archmages, the first wizards.<br>The Ancient Archmages spent many years accumulating power and weapons. They were also secretly spreading knowledge of arcane practice across Argena, creating more wizards. Eventually, the Anteity League betrayed their leaders in the Battle for <a data-href="Caelum Insula" href="http://wiki.alexsievert.com/argena/caelum-insula.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Caelum Insula</a>, also known as the Divine Betrayal. This marks the beginning of the Scourge.<br>The Scourge lasted for roughly 50 years. During it, the Anteity League decimated the Gods. At this point, there were three parties fighting. The forces of the upper and lower planes still fought against each other, which the Ancient Archmages capitalized on, killing multiple avatars of the Gods and even managing to kill <a data-href="Naivara" href="http://wiki.alexsievert.com/argena/gods/naivara.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Naivara</a> herself (who was later resurrected during the Astral Devastation). <br>The Scourge ended during the Battle of the Planes, where the Gods finally "defeated" the Ancient Archmages. Upon realizing they were about to truly die, the deities from both sides combined their power to banish all of the Ancients to the far corners of the multiverse.<br>After banishing the Ancient Archmages, the Gods drafted the Abdication Accords, agreeing to never walk the Material Plane again, in the hope of avoiding a conflict like the Scourge again. This ushered in an age known as the Chandari Dark Ages.<br><br>The Chandari Dark Ages are a period of time just after the Scourge where most of the Pre-Dissension city-states were destroyed during the 450 years of fighting and nearly all of the followers of the Anteity League were killed by the Gods, losing most of their arcane knowledge. The knowledge did survive with the few remaining apprentices of the Ancients however, and would eventually make a comeback.<br>The Dark Ages were a time of rebuilding mostly. The relatively few survivors took to reestablishing and rebuilding the societies that had been lost to war. It was during this time that people that had once been separated by the old institutions now relied on each other to survive and reconstruct a new semblance of life. A period of unparalleled mixing of people and ideas began.<br>The Dark Ages ended in 189 PS, when the Ancient Blue Dragon Thalroth the Storm Wyrm took advantage of the Post-Dissension power vacuum and conjured a massive tempest that covered the entire continent for 2 weeks, forcing the Coalition of Free Peoples to surrender to him or else their kingdoms would be destroyed. This event is known as the Rending of Skies, and it is what started the Age of Dragons.<br><br>The Age of Dragons was a period of around 300 years that started in 189 PS with Thalroth the Storm Wyrm subjugating the Coalition of Free Peoples. With Thalroth in power, other dragons began using their innate magical powers to terrorize cities and accumulate their own hoards. Thalroth was fine with this, as long as the dragons under him paid him a steep tribute.<br>Along with the dragons, other intelligent creatures began plundering and controlling parts of Chandaria as well. Fiends, aberrations, and even sentient beasts seized the opportunity for wealth. Thalroth allowed all of this, as long as tribute was paid. He realized that the humanoids were the only group powerful enough to usurp him, so by keeping them living in fear by allowing all types of different tyrants to decimate their civilization, he kept himself in power.<br>As his underlings came and went, Thalroth remained in power for nearly 300 years. Eventually, a group of heroes slayed him in 419 PS, ushering in a new era of humanoid prosperity.<br><br>The Arcane Resurgence immediately followed the Age of Dragons. With Thalroth defeated, the people of Chandaria promptly liberated themselves from those who once served him. With their newfound freedom, people once again had the time and power to pursue new ideas and technologies. Free from the oppression of the dragons, powerful mages from before the Age of Dragons took advantage of the focus on new ideas to spread a new ideology surrounding the use of magic.<br>They called it Kainomancy, or <a data-href="The Kainomantic Principles" href="http://wiki.alexsievert.com/argena/chandaria/chandarian-history/the-kainomantic-principles.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">The Kainomantic Principles</a>. It was developed as an antithesis to the Anteitic Principles. Rather than destruction and power, they instead focused on unity and ethics. Kainomancy preached about magic as a force that connects everything in the world. In an era of unmatched growth and innovation, the Kainomantic Principles spread rapidly. The ways of the Ancient Archmages, died out and magic thrived under a new ethos.<br>However, the Kainomantic Principles weren't perfect either. One thing that mages still struggled with was the balance between experimentation and ethics. In order to support the rapid innovation of magical practices, large parts of the world were devastated for resources. Mountains were leveled and dwarves were exploited in search of the newly discovered <a data-href="Harmonium" href="http://wiki.alexsievert.com/argena/harmonium.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Harmonium</a> crystals. During this time, most of the <a data-href="Westerwood" href="http://wiki.alexsievert.com/argena/chandaria/chandarian-history/pre-dissension/westerwood.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Westerwood</a> was deforested for its Elderbark trees, which also were found to produce similar effects as Harmonium.<br>The Arcane Resurgence lasted for just over 500 years. It ended in 983 PS, when a massive army from the Astral Plane descended from the heavens and invaded the Material Plane. The war lasted for 11 years, and it irrevocably changed the world.<br><br>Scholars now know that the Astral Devastation began because Kainomancers began using the Elderbark trees to experiment with interplanar travel. However, they experimented too much, and weakened the Interplanar Fabric between the Material and Astral Planes. The mages didn't know it at the time, but beings on the other side took note of this infringement on their planar border.<br>One night in 983 PS, giant rifts opened in the night sky. Gith soldiers and astral aberrations poured out of the rifts. They set upon the major cities of Argena, so-called beacon cities, and sought to destroy most of human civilization in one massive attack. Many cities fell, but a few were able to fend off the first wave of attackers. Spellhaven was one such city that survived the initial attack. This invading force would soon come to be known as the Cosmic Imperium. Over the coming days, the inhabitants of Argena realized they would have to adjust to a new way of life, as after the initial attack, the sun did not rise the next morning, nor the next. The Cosmic Imperium had somehow halted the progress of the heavens and stuck Argena in a state of eternal night.<br>The Imperium set up bastions across Chandaria and all of Argena to cement their influence in the areas that they controlled. They destroyed any sort of mortal resistance that remained in the controlled territories and many nation leaders were forced to either submit to the invaders or cede most of their land and retreat to stronghold cities.<br>As the war progressed, the Kainomantic Principles began to crumble. Some mages began embracing the new psionic abilities that the Imperium was using. They became initiated in the psionic ways of the Cosmic Imperium. Other mages turned away from the Kainomantic Principles and reverted to using magic in forbidden Anteitic ways. Few true Kainomancers remained.<br>The beginning of the final resistance started when a group of mages from Spellhaven took up a seemingly impossible task. They set out to resurrect Naivara, the Goddess of the Moon. They thought that she would be able to end the eternal night and give the Material Plane inhabitants an advantage over the Imperium. They travelled to the edges of the Astral Plane where it was said that Naivara's soul remained. They performed a forbidden ritual to reconnect her soul with its body, and Naivara was reborn. She was grateful, and bestowed upon them the Aegis of the Veil, a relic with the power to seal the rifts in the Interplanar Fabric. Unfortunately for the mages, that was the most she could do to thank them, without further breaking the abdication accords.<br>The Aegis became more than just a tool. The mages used the Aegis as a symbol to rally the remaining mortal resistance. That same group travelled around Argena gathering local resistances and sealing the minor rifts around the world. The resistance suffered great losses, but they managed to seal all of the rifts on Argena except for one.<br>The Battle of Limmedorrn's Rift was the climax of the Astral Devastation. It took place in the sky near where modern-day Sella Alora is. This rift was the largest that the Cosmic Imperium had created and was the main supply line into the Material Plane. The united forces of the mortal resistance first assaulted the bastion that had been built below the rift. Once they had control of the ground, they launched their attack into the sky to the actual rift. Wielding the Aegis of the Veil, a mage by the name of Ilothar Ilbrie, one of the original mages from Spellhaven who resurrected Naivara, fought through the Imperium's forces and managed to complete the sealing ritual, closing the rift for good, but dying in the process. The remaining Imperium soldiers fought for a while, but eventual the survivors either surrendered or fled, hiding in small groups across Argena.<br><br>In the aftermath of the Astral Devastation, mortal spirits were high. One of the generals of the mortal army at the Battle of Limmedorrn's Rift, named Godrick Lansen began making himself very known across Chandaria. He travelled around to the beacon cities, riling up the survivors and invoking the martyrdom of Ilothar Ilbrie. Godrick preached the need for mortals to expand their influence by travelling to other planes and colonizing them. This platform would have seemed radical in most contexts, but following the Astral Devastation and the victory over the Cosmic Imperium, people bought into it, and Godrick gained a sizable following.<br>Godrick used his influence in Spellhaven to start the construction of the Planar Nexus. This device was the pinnacle of all of the arcane knowledge gained over the course of the Arcane Resurgence and the Astral Devastation. It allowed large groups of people to travel to any plane of existence that they wanted.<br>Using the Nexus, Chandarian forces spread across the multiverse. They began conquering large regions on many other planes. The forces of the other planes were caught by surprise and fell to the Chandarian conquerors. The colonizers set up outposts in the conquered regions.<br>For the next 400 years, Chandarian influence spread across the planes, but it was not without challenge. Starting around 1300 PS, internal and external resistance pushed against Chandarian influence. Chandarian forces on the elemental plane of air were defeated and control of the plane of air was lost.<br>This defeat made some Chandarians realize that they were no different than the Cosmic Imperium of a past age. Revolutionaries from Chandaria secretly met with conquered people from other planes. They began planning an attack that would end this era of colonialism.<br>In 1423 PS, a small guerilla force composed of Chandarians and extraplanar revolutionaries attacked the Planar Nexus in Spellhaven. With a highly coordinated attack, the group gained access to the Nexus and destroyed it. With a massive explosion, the Planar Nexus was sundered, and the continent's connection to the other planes was severed.<br>Left to fend for themselves, the Chandarian outposts on the other planes succumbed to local uprisings or were assimilated into the planes themselves. Meanwhile on the Material Plane, Chandaria's economy collapsed. Having become reliant on exotic resources from other planes, the whole continent fell into disarray. The empire that had been established through the interplanar colonization began falling apart. Political alliances crumbled and many cities and regions fell into isolationism.<br><br>For roughly the next century, the fractured independent states were left on their own to heal from the Sundering of the Nexus and the end of the Age of Dominion. The expansionist ideologies of the previous age quickly lost traction and new philosophies of peace and cooperation spread.<br>The Era of Reconciliation was a period of discovery for many. People had time to think about the institutions of the past and their cyclical failures. There was a complete cultural reset across Chandaria.<br>Some independent city-states began forming alliances again based on trade and mutual defense. The most notable was the growing Larenthian Alliance, ran by Lawrence Galaven. The Alliance was officially founded in 1508 PS, which is widely considered to be the official end of the Era of Reconciliation and the start of the Age of Peace.<br><br>Learning from the past failures of the world, Chandaria entered into what is known as the Age of Peace. This Age of Peace is the current age of the world. No notable global-scale incursions have happened since 1500 PS that would mark the start of a new age.]]></description><link>http://wiki.alexsievert.com/argena/chandaria/chandarian-history/an-overall-history-of-chandaria.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Argena/Chandaria/Chandarian History/An Overall History Of Chandaria.md</guid><pubDate>Thu, 30 Jan 2025 02:14:36 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[The Anteitic Principles of Magic]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br>The Ancient Archmages of the Anteity League were the first mortals to learn how to use arcane spellcasting. As their coalition grew and they secretly spread knowledge of the arcane arts to other mortals, they found it necessary to establish a core system of philosophy on the usage of magic. They came up with their "4 Pillars of Magic". They are:<br><br>Since the Archmages saw magic as the divide between gods and mortals, it was in their eyes a tool of control. They believed that magic exists as a means to impose one's will upon the world, shaping reality to match the caster's desires. Power was their ultimate goal, but not power over their fellow mortals. Instead it was power over the world, and by extension the Gods.<br><br>In the eyes of the Anteity League, anyone who refused to learn the arcane arts were indirectly supporting the oppressive gods. They saw the caster as the center of all magical power. They saw intellect as paramount above all else, and those who weren't smart enough to wield the power of magic were a lost cause. This idea of the caster being the center of magic led to further ideas that no external force, whether divine, natural, or arcane, should dictate how magic is used.<br><br>As a result of their ultimate goal to rid the world of divine influence, the Ancient Archmages became very engrossed in the idea that sometimes true progress can only be achieved through the destruction of the old order, making way for something new. This principle was used as justification for a lot of their actions that resulted in carnage.<br><br>Arcane magic is inherently connected to experimentation and invention. The Archmages were pioneers in the field and created most of the fundamentals that are still used today. Because of this, they believed that progress requires pushing boundaries, even at great cost. No cost was too much for the advancement of arcane theory. Ethics and morality were of little concern to the Ancient Archmages.]]></description><link>http://wiki.alexsievert.com/argena/chandaria/chandarian-history/the-anteitic-principles-of-magic.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Argena/Chandaria/Chandarian History/The Anteitic Principles of Magic.md</guid><pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2024 06:08:31 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[The Great Dissension]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br>Gods of the upper planes fought the gods of the lower planes for control over all realms. The war ultimately ended in a stalemate, and further reinforced the split between the upper and lower planes. Remnants of this war can be seen everywhere. On all planes, ancient remains of gods killed in this war can be found. Creatures still exist that witnessed the Great Dissension but they are few and far between and often choose to isolate themselves from the modern society. Many religions can also be traced back to this war as well, as gods recruited mortals to fight on their sides, spawning religions for those gods.<br><br>During the Great Dissension. The Gods taught mortals how to harness the arcane power of the weave, creating the first great wizards, the Ancient Archmages. The Ancients gained enough power through the Gods to create their own god-killing weapons. Gods were killed during the Great Dissension, leaving their bodies strewn across the material plane. Eventually, the Ancient Archmages realized that they had power that rivalled the Gods, and decided to band together and turn on them, thus starting The Scourge. The alliance of the Ancients became known as the Antiety League. The lower and upper Gods remained fighting each other, while the Ancients entered the fight as a third party. At the climax of the Scourge, the Battle of the Planes, the gods were forced to combine forces and channel all of their power to banish the Ancient Archmages to the far corners of the Multiverse.<br>
After banishing the Archmages, the surviving gods convened and signed the Abdication Accords. This agreement, signed by all gods in attendance, stated that they would not walk the Material Plane again, and they would do their best to stay out of mortal affairs. The effectiveness of this agreement is up for debate, but it did seriously cut down on the amount of gods actually on the Material Plane. Divine influence is still alive and well though through their followers.<br><br>Powerful magical items remain from the Great Dissension. The Ancients constructed lairs, vaults to store their god-killing weapons, and other powerful magic items that they created. When the Ancients were split up and banished to the edges of the Multiverse, they left behind these weapons and artifacts in their vaults, which took the form of towers, underground ruins, old forts, and mansions, posing as the premier dungeons for the most ambitious of adventurers.<br><br>During the Dissension, the Ancient Archmages spread arcane knowledge and technologies across the Material Plane in a slight of the Gods. This explains the existence of a lot of the uncommon magic items found across the world in various ruins and whatnot. These technologies were abandoned in those ruins at some point during the Dissension due to the owners being slain in the war or leaving them behind. The pervasive nature of these uncommon and slightly rare magical items are also in part thanks to lesser mages that began practicing the arcane arts inspired by the Ancients.]]></description><link>http://wiki.alexsievert.com/argena/chandaria/chandarian-history/the-great-dissension.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Argena/Chandaria/Chandarian History/The Great Dissension.md</guid><pubDate>Mon, 03 Jun 2024 23:16:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[The Kainomantic Principles of Magic]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br>Kainomancy is an ideology developed during the early days of the Arcane Resurgence. It was created as a direct opposition to the Anteitic Principles. Instead of the destruction and power of the Anteitic Principles, Kainomancy focuses on unity and ethics instead. The Kainomantic Principles are as follows:<br><br><br>For the new generation of mages, magic was not a tool for dominion, but rather a force to bring balance between individuals, societies, and nature. The shifting of the main goal of magic is instrumental in the difference between the Kainomantic and Anteitic Principles. It served as the basis for the other new ideas of Kainomancy.<br><br>While the Ancient Archmages tried to spread the power of magic to all mortals, their archaic beliefs led them to inadvertently creating an elitist class system based on magical prowess. The Kainomantic Principles attempted to fix this by shifting the concept of magic to a shared resource that everyone interacts with in some form, regardless of their intellectual ability.<br><br>To the new mages, one of the biggest failings of the Anteitic Principles was the infatuation with the complete destructions of old systems. They correctly deduced that this was the reason for the most destructive actions of the Ancient Archmages. In an attempt to acknowledge the original reason for the focus on destruction while still remaining constructive, they shifted to the idea that magic is a means to repair the damage of the past, rather than to completely uproot. This was mostly manifested through a focus on innovation in arcane technologies and research.<br><br>As a reinforcement of the overall theme of Kainomancy, the last principle is simply that magic is a bridge between mortals, the world, the divine, and each other. The strength of this idea came from the fact that it has a basis in reality. It was known at the time that The Weave was merely an interface to connect with the raw magical power that suffuses the universe. This raw magic is said to be a part of the goddess Harmonia herself. So in that sense magic really is a force of connection between all these different entities.<br><br>The Kainomantic Principles had a profound effect on many people's views of the arcane. Casters and non-casters alike were swept up in a newfound sense of unity. People were drawn to the positivity of Kainomancy, and it quickly became the dominant ideology, and the Anteitic principles were mostly extinguished.<br>The effects of Kainomancy were not all positive though. One thing to note about the Kainomantic Principles is that they say nothing in opposition of the "Unfettered Experimentation" pillar of the Anteitic Principles. Consequently, the Arcane Resurgence saw rampant innovation at the cost of the natural world. Mountains were leveled in search of the newly discovered Harmonium, and the <a data-href="Westerwood" href="http://wiki.alexsievert.com/argena/chandaria/chandarian-history/pre-dissension/westerwood.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Westerwood</a> was heavily deforested for its Elderbark trees.]]></description><link>http://wiki.alexsievert.com/argena/chandaria/chandarian-history/the-kainomantic-principles.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Argena/Chandaria/Chandarian History/The Kainomantic Principles.md</guid><pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2024 07:03:57 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Atrisean Dynasty]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br>Capital City: Sella Alora<br>Sella Alora rests at the bottom of the Exalted Summit. This location is supposed to show the Dynasty's ties to the gods. The entire city is adorned in gold and rare metals to show the vast wealth of the Dynasty.]]></description><link>http://wiki.alexsievert.com/argena/chandaria/nations/atrisean-dynasty/atrisean-dynasty.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Argena/Chandaria/Nations/Atrisean Dynasty/Atrisean Dynasty.md</guid><pubDate>Fri, 19 Jan 2024 07:09:08 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Essaheim]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br>Population: 93,460 (80% dwarves, 10% human, 5% drow, 5% other races)<br>Government: Right to rule in Essaheim is based on two main ideas: material wealth and blood relation. Clans have been known to run the city for over a hundred years at a time. The transitions of power between clans is almost always hostile, and often violent. The current ruling clan is the Fireforge clan, with the head of the city being Bergmann Dworic. The title of Bergmann (meaning miner) is the highest in the court of Essaheim. The Bergmann has a council of Stadras composed of other Fireforge members and also other members of the wealthy elite that live on The Isles.<br>Defense: Essaheim benefits from a naturally defensible position. There is one entrance into the city, through the Tormor Gate. The Tormor Gate is a large, hundred foot tall adamantine door that is guarded by siege weapons and archers on the walls, as well as a medium sized garrison of Watchmen on the ground. The actual city has a strong Watchmen presence, with less in the Isles and Upper Echelons, and more in the Sprawl. The main barracks of the Watchmen is at the Crown's Barracks in the Isles. The Burgess Castle employs its own personal staff of guards.<br>Commerce: Essaheim's main export is minerals and gems from the mines, as well as the accompanying metal goods that are made from the mined metal. The great Forges of Essaheim are known for being a large producer of steel and brass, as well as occasionally striking a large vein of adamantium. All manner of metal goods can be bought in the Artisan District and the Stallyard of the Upper Echelons. Essaheim imports a lot of its food since it is hard to grow underground. One of the Isles has a beam of sunlight shining on it through the ceiling of the cavern. This Isle is known as the Inselhof and is where the majority of the inhabitants of the Isles get their food. The Galastari Academy is also rumored to have its own food production through magical means, but no one on the outside knows. Common and uncommon magic items can be bought in the Artisan District of the Upper Echelons. They are often created by former members of the Galastari Academy.<br>Organizations: The Galastari Academy is the largest independent organization in the city. It is the home of all things Abjuration-related. It is also the keeper of all knowledge in the city. Because of this, certain pieces of knowledge are often kept from the public, as the Galastari feel it doesn't belong in their hands. The Miner's Guild is also very important in the city. The head of the Miner's Guild is Erias Steelfist who oversees all mining operations. The Miner's Guild works very closely with the Smelter's Guild, which are two different groups. The Smelter's guild oversees the Great Forges, and controls all production and outgoing commodities. The Order of the Cerulean Owl is a secret organization within the city that seeks truth in all aspects of life. They are ardently against the Galastari Academy's gatekeeping of knowledge. The order is sometimes called 'The Suits' due to the members often sporting very dapper suits. Members will sometimes refer to other members as 'Owls'. Members of the order come from all societal classes, which gives them a huge insight into all the parts of Essaheim. The Order of the Cerulean Owl headquarters are in the Upper Echelons at the Enlightened Owl library.<br>Essaheim was founded and constructed in the fallout of the <a class="internal-link" data-href="The Great Dissension.md" href="http://wiki.alexsievert.com/argena/chandaria/chandarian-history/the-great-dissension.html" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Great Dissension</a>. Dwarves who fought alongside <a data-href="Reicha" href="http://wiki.alexsievert.com/argena/gods/reicha.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Reicha</a> retreated into the mountain to continue their search for wealth and treasure. Parts of the caverns of Essaheim date back to the pre-dissension age. Extremely old ruins can be found here and it is even possible to take tours of certain pre-dissension caverns. The dwarves are fairly accepting of all gods but <a data-href="Reicha" href="http://wiki.alexsievert.com/argena/gods/reicha.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Reicha</a> is the only deity with public shrines, since the majority of Essaheim worships <a data-href="Reicha" href="http://wiki.alexsievert.com/argena/gods/reicha.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Reicha</a> in some sense. Essaheim sits as the major manufacturer of smithy goods and exporter of minerals in Southeast Chandaria, supplying both <a class="internal-link" data-href="The Kingdom of Falstor.md" href="http://wiki.alexsievert.com/argena/chandaria/nations/falstor/the-kingdom-of-falstor.html" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Falstor</a> to the south and Rodigia to the north of the Hawgnoze mountains. Since Essaheim has such a large population, it is host to all manners of social classes. Among the trade hubs of the cities is an extensive mingling of ideas. However, due to the stubbornness of Dwarves, most permanent residents of Essaheim rarely differ in moral code and beliefs.<br>The majority of the lower class in the Sprawl is made up of miners, fishermen, and other general laborers. In the bottom of the main cavern of Essaheim by the Sprawl is an extensive river network that weaves around all of the Isles. These rivers that sit at the bottom level of the Sprawl are used mainly for fishing, feeding the people of the Sprawl, as well as being used for transportation between major parts of the Sprawl. The middle class inhabits the Upper Echelons. While it is not against any rules for residents of the Sprawl to visit the Upper Echelons, there is a fee for people that don't live or work in the Upper Echelons to use the Grand Lift to get up to the Upper Echelons. The Upper Echelons is mostly made up of soldiers, artisans, and merchants, as well as the members of the Galastari Academy. Middle class folks that live in the Upper Echelons are free to travel between there and the Sprawl, but still not allowed to visit the Isles except on invitation. The residents of the Isles are the elite class. They are comprised of guild masters, merchant lords, and minor political figures, as well as the farmers that live on the Inselhof. Residents of the Isles are allowed to travel anywhere within Essaheim, including the public areas of the Burgess Castle (on account of the fact that the majority of the elite class know someone within the castle).<br><br>Bergmann Dworic is the highest official in the government. He deals with high-level diplomatic issues and decisions that affect all of Essaheim. Dworic is actually a fairly well-liked leader. He is known as an advocate for the middle class and supports the city's artisans fervently. Some people don't like Dworic because they think he doesn't care for the lower class and sometimes makes decisions that are super biased toward the elite class. However, this is not Dworic's fault. The Stadras are heavily paid off by the elite class, so they advise the king into unknowingly making decisions that only benefit the elite class. The Stadras carry out their conspiracy through the Supreme Richter Nora Hammerstone. The Supreme Richter is the highest judge in the city, and so has the final say on all law matters. The Cerulean Owls have some leads into this conspiracy but haven't fully uncovered it yet. The Supreme Richter works closely with the Watchmaster Dain Aranore, who is the leader of the Watchmen. The Watchmaster is not a part of the conspiracy and is simply following orders from the Supreme Richter.<br>Notable Buildings<br>Upper Echelons:<br>Artisans District:<br>The Eversharp Anvil  Blacksmith owned by Gilmur Eversharp. He will make whatever basic metal items the group wants commissioned. A small item costs 3 gp, a medium item costs 10 gp, and a large metal item costs 30 gp. If the party wants armor or weapons, they can commission him to make one which will take a while, or they can go to an armorer or weaponsmith in the Stallyard to see what's already been made. Gilmur's apprentice is his son Gilthor.<br>Hammer &amp; Brawn  Blacksmith owned by Olric Stoutleg. He will also make basic metal items commissioned by the party. A small item costs 5 gp, a medium item costs 15 gp, and a large metal item costs 35 gp. He also has weapons and armor for sale in the Stallyard. Olric has no apprentice and does all the work himself.<br>Beloril's Bows  Bowyer owned by Beloril Orcbane. He makes various bows and crossbows. All prices follow the player's handbook prices. His goods are also for sale at the weapons shop in the Stallyard. Beloril offers to take any magical woods that the players have and turn them into magical bows.<br>The Enlightened Owl  Library acting as a secret headquarters for the Order of the Cerulean Owl. The head librarian is a human man named Bredon Donall. He has reddish brown middle length hair parted to one side with a very neatly trimmed beard and spectacles. He's dressed in a very respectable suit.<br>Shanek's Shrooms - Shanek Grassfoot comes from a long line of mushroom farmers. Mushroom cultivation has never really taken off in Essaheim, but Shanek is adamant that it is the next big thing. He is a very excitable businessman who is always excited about people taking an interest in his mushrooms. He'll sell people a sample of his Gloomglow mushrooms.<br>Shrine to Reicha  A small shrine to the Goddess Reicha. small shrine to the Goddess Reicha. It is built into the side of the stalactite, with the statue carved out of the stone. Flowers, candles, and gold coins lay around the statue.]]></description><link>http://wiki.alexsievert.com/argena/chandaria/nations/essaheim/essaheim.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Argena/Chandaria/Nations/Essaheim/Essaheim.md</guid><pubDate>Mon, 10 Jun 2024 22:24:58 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[The Great Purge of Dalonstor]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br>The Great Purge happened in 2479 PS, when members from the House Alystri crossed into the fishing waters claimed by the House Rocco, and were attacked on the water by soldiers from Rocco. The House Alystri claimed that the area that they had been in did not actually belong to Rocco, and was actually international waters. As soon as the House Alystri discovered that their ship had been attacked, they retaliated by making a house call to Rocco and torching part of the Rocco manor. During the fight, a number of the Alystri attackers were killed. Rocco went on a counter attack and began killing anyone in the street that they saw wearing the Alystri crest. Martial Law was declared in the city for 3 days as the fighting continued in the streets. At the end of the battle, there was only one survivor from the House Alystri, Sylas, who lived in a house off the Alystri grounds and fended off a group of Rocco soldiers by himself. He made his way to a safehouse and hunkered down, until the House Rocco believed that Alystri was completely eliminated. Eventually, Sylas rebuilt the House Alystri to its former strength.]]></description><link>http://wiki.alexsievert.com/argena/chandaria/nations/falstor/historical-events/the-great-purge-of-dalonstor.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Argena/Chandaria/Nations/Falstor/Historical Events/The Great Purge of Dalonstor.md</guid><pubDate>Sun, 18 Feb 2024 05:47:51 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Dalonstor]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br><br>The population of Dalonstor is 32,538 (52% Humans, 29% Elves, 7% Dwarves, 7% Halflings, 5% Other).<br><br>The government in Dalonstor has a strong history of corruption, and the current mayor, Reev Rocc is no different. The mayor holds ultimate control over the city, and chooses their council members when they are elected. Election is a generous word to describe the choosing of the mayor. Every year during Planimor, an election is held where any citizen of the kingdom is welcome to run for mayor. However, everyone knows that without a violent upheaval, there is no chance of beating the incumbent. Political opponents tend to go missing too.<br><br>The city of Dalonstor itself boasts little in the means of defensive structures. There are no walls and no siege equipment. Rather, most of the military might of Dalonstor is supplied by the neighboring capital city of Falstor. The only armed force that belongs to Dalonstor itself is the Nightstalkers, a new group created by Reev Rocc to keep the peace in the city. <br><br>Dalonstor is above all else a naval powerhouse. Situated on the coast of the Azure Expanse, the city began as a simple fishing town and trading post, and then grew to become the Kingdom's largest shipyard. The Kingdom of Falstor boasts a very strong navy, not quite as strong as No'zaral or the Atrisean Dynasty, but by far the most powerful in Eastern Chandaria. All maritime trade for Falstor goes through the ports of Dalonstor, but the citizens never seem to see any of this money, it all goes up to the capital city. Most of the money that circulates through the city itself comes from fishing instead. The fishing waters of the coast are controlled by the 4 most powerful families in the city, the Houses of Mason, Pili, Rocc, and Alystri. These Houses are constantly vying with each other for influence in the city. To them, controlling the fish is controlling the city.<br><br>The Mayor of Dalonstor is often also called the King's Steward. The Mayor is the leader of the Steward's Council, which consists of the mayor, the leader of the fishing guild, the Captain of the Watch, the leader of the shipwright's guild, and the Champion of the Arena. The Steward's council controls essentially everything in the city. It just so happens that when Reev Rocc took of the city, he installed his family members into all of the positions on the Steward's Council. These days, any slight against House Rocc means the entire city turning against you. The only institution independent of the Steward's Council is the <br><br>Dalonstor was chartered in 2037 PS, when King Reudan of the newly created Kingdom of Falstor decided that it was necessary for their nation to establish maritime trade routes to build positive relations with the surrounding nations of Rodigia and Stormion, and to expand the city of Falstor's fishing market. A small settlement of around 100 people set up a small village on the coast, and began constructing fishing and trading vessels, as well as the King's Steps.<br><br>Life in early Dalonstor was miserable. The inhabitants worked from dawn to dusk building ships, cleaning fish, hauling stone, and constructing the King's Steps. One man, a dwarf named Uhtred Wavebreaker, took it upon himself to keep the people of Dalonstor entertained. In his backyard, he constructed a small wooden ring and named it The Trench. Here, he started a fighting club for the local fisherman and the traveling vagabonds that made their way through the town on the way to Falstor. The Trench ended up becoming extremely popular, and Uhtred quickly gained enough money to build a dedicated arena.<br>As the Trench grew larger, fighters from further and further came to prove themselves in the arena. People also called the Trench "The Great Arena of Dalonstor". Uhtred Wavebreaker became very much a legend in the arena, as the founder and first champion of the arena.<br><br>As Dalonstor grew, 6 families sought power more than the rest: Alystri, Mason, Pili, Rocc, Liadon, and Wymar. These families all had stakes in both the fishing industry and the shipbuilding industry. They killed each other over fishing territory, building technology, and even romantic affairs. In 2189 PS, in a feud over a new shipbuilding technique, House Pili slaughtered House Wymar, killing all of its members and burning the Wymar Manor to the ground. Known as the Night of Embers, it sparked discussion among the houses. They all convened and signed the House Combat Compromise. Through this agreement, the houses agreed that whichever house the champion of the arena belonged to would hold the ultimate bargaining power in house feuds. Because of this, the arena became even more central to life in Dalonstor.<br>In 2251 PS, Oriana of house Liadon married Prince Rolan III of Falstor. King Rolan II was very old at the time of the wedding, and Rolan III was crowned King the following year. House Liadon moved out of Dalonstor and became a royal house in the city of Falstor.<br>The remaining 4 houses: Alystri, Mason, Pili, and Rocc remain to this day, and are still constantly feuding. The modern houses each have about 20 members and 20 loyal retinue soldiers per house. Alystri and Rocc are the 2 most powerful houses, but since House Rocc holds all spots on the Steward's Council, Alystri is heavily persecuted by them.]]></description><link>http://wiki.alexsievert.com/argena/chandaria/nations/falstor/dalonstor.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Argena/Chandaria/Nations/Falstor/Dalonstor.md</guid><pubDate>Tue, 09 Jul 2024 18:55:30 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Falstor]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br>Capital city of the Kingdom of Falstor, ruled over by King Ophal.]]></description><link>http://wiki.alexsievert.com/argena/chandaria/nations/falstor/falstor.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Argena/Chandaria/Nations/Falstor/Falstor.md</guid><pubDate>Fri, 19 Jan 2024 07:09:14 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Marais]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br>One of the premier tourist areas in the Kingdom of Falstor. People come here to get a glimpse of life in the wilderness, in the depths of the swamp.]]></description><link>http://wiki.alexsievert.com/argena/chandaria/nations/falstor/marais.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Argena/Chandaria/Nations/Falstor/Marais.md</guid><pubDate>Fri, 19 Jan 2024 07:09:15 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Marrisburg]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br>Town built around the Alltree, with a flourishing druidic order in the town.]]></description><link>http://wiki.alexsievert.com/argena/chandaria/nations/falstor/marrisburg.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Argena/Chandaria/Nations/Falstor/Marrisburg.md</guid><pubDate>Fri, 19 Jan 2024 07:09:15 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[The Kingdom of Falstor]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br>]]></description><link>http://wiki.alexsievert.com/argena/chandaria/nations/falstor/the-kingdom-of-falstor.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Argena/Chandaria/Nations/Falstor/The Kingdom of Falstor.md</guid><pubDate>Fri, 19 Jan 2024 07:07:02 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Arcane Revolution]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br>In 2490 PS, the church of <a data-href="Harmonia" href="http://wiki.alexsievert.com/argena/gods/harmonia.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Harmonia</a> in <a data-href="Galvenport" href="http://wiki.alexsievert.com/argena/chandaria/nations/larenthian-alliance/provinces/galvenport.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Galvenport</a> colluded with certain members of the headmasters of Wizendell to try and seize control of <a data-href="Galvenport" href="http://wiki.alexsievert.com/argena/chandaria/nations/larenthian-alliance/provinces/galvenport.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Galvenport</a> and take over the <a class="internal-link" data-href="The Larenthian Alliance.md" href="http://wiki.alexsievert.com/argena/chandaria/nations/larenthian-alliance/the-larenthian-alliance.html" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Alliance</a>. The revolution was put down by Chief Magnate Thedric Alfir and the Church of <a data-href="Harmonia" href="http://wiki.alexsievert.com/argena/gods/harmonia.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Harmonia</a> was disbanded and demolished, and worship of <a data-href="Harmonia" href="http://wiki.alexsievert.com/argena/gods/harmonia.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Harmonia</a> was banned.]]></description><link>http://wiki.alexsievert.com/argena/chandaria/nations/larenthian-alliance/historical-events/arcane-revolution.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Argena/Chandaria/Nations/Larenthian Alliance/Historical Events/Arcane Revolution.md</guid><pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 02:57:19 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Ankheg Grove]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br>Ankheg Grove's monster storage facilities are definitely the most impressive out of any in Holfirth Province. Because of the Ankhegs' burrowing ability, they need to be stored in full metal cages. "Ankheg Alley" as it's called by the villagers, is an area piled high with metal cages and various pulley systems for transporting creatures and people between cages.]]></description><link>http://wiki.alexsievert.com/argena/chandaria/nations/larenthian-alliance/provinces/holfirth-province/ankheg-grove.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Argena/Chandaria/Nations/Larenthian Alliance/Provinces/Holfirth Province/Ankheg Grove.md</guid><pubDate>Wed, 28 Feb 2024 05:49:49 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Basilham]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br>Like its name suggests, Basilham specializes in harvesting Basilisk venom. The venom serves two purposes: it can be used to paralyze people, and it is also used to produce the antidote for the paralysis. Basilham's local alchemists have become renowned across the province for their mastery in brewing potions. The mastery pales in comparison to that of <a data-href="Wizendell" href="http://wiki.alexsievert.com/argena/chandaria/nations/larenthian-alliance/provinces/wizendell.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Wizendell</a> or <a data-href="Galvenport" href="http://wiki.alexsievert.com/argena/chandaria/nations/larenthian-alliance/provinces/galvenport.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Galvenport</a>, but it is very good for what the villagers need.]]></description><link>http://wiki.alexsievert.com/argena/chandaria/nations/larenthian-alliance/provinces/holfirth-province/basilham.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Argena/Chandaria/Nations/Larenthian Alliance/Provinces/Holfirth Province/Basilham.md</guid><pubDate>Wed, 28 Feb 2024 05:49:52 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Dire Wolf Grotto]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br>Mayor: Barenas Graumil (Half-Elf Male)<br>
Overseer: Lezre Morel (Half-Orc Female)<br>Dire Wolf Grotto is a harvesting town that focuses on capturing, raising, and harvesting the dire wolves from the Shadowwood Forest. The village has around 50 people that live in the town center and surrounding areas. Some say that the day that the wolf pens of Dire Wolf Grotto go silent, the province will collapse. The local archive, The Lupine Archives, keeps texts on business dealings, local legends, and harvesting standards among other things.]]></description><link>http://wiki.alexsievert.com/argena/chandaria/nations/larenthian-alliance/provinces/holfirth-province/dire-wolf-grotto.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Argena/Chandaria/Nations/Larenthian Alliance/Provinces/Holfirth Province/Dire Wolf Grotto.md</guid><pubDate>Wed, 28 Feb 2024 05:49:58 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Fermenton]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br>Fermenton is the main location for food production in the province. While Holfirth does have its own farm fields, it also benefits from Fermenton's farm production. Fermenton contains both animal pastures and crop fields. It's main exports are wheat, corn, and beef. Despite being a somewhat small village, Fermenton is known for its night life scene. There are multiple taverns and even a small music venue in the town. Travellers and locals alike are known to go on "tavern crawls" in the village all the time. The most popular tavern in the town is the Open Arms Tavern.]]></description><link>http://wiki.alexsievert.com/argena/chandaria/nations/larenthian-alliance/provinces/holfirth-province/fermenton.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Argena/Chandaria/Nations/Larenthian Alliance/Provinces/Holfirth Province/Fermenton.md</guid><pubDate>Wed, 28 Feb 2024 05:50:01 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Fisk]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br>Fisk is one of the poorest areas in the Holfirth Province. Most of the houses here are built of simple sticks and thatch. Part of the village extends out onto the water of the Eldermere Lake.<br>
This village's major export is fish. It supplies most of the province with food, though most of its exports go to <a data-href="Holfirth" href="http://wiki.alexsievert.com/argena/chandaria/nations/larenthian-alliance/provinces/holfirth-province/holfirth.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Holfirth</a>. There is also a small shipyard here that deals in vessels that travel further into the lake than the shallows. The shipyard rarely sees serious business however, because most people are too scared to travel beyond the shallows due to tales of sirens and sea monsters. Those that do travel across the lake rarely return.]]></description><link>http://wiki.alexsievert.com/argena/chandaria/nations/larenthian-alliance/provinces/holfirth-province/fisk.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Argena/Chandaria/Nations/Larenthian Alliance/Provinces/Holfirth Province/Fisk.md</guid><pubDate>Wed, 28 Feb 2024 05:50:04 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Holfirth]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br>Population: 5,274 (55% Human, 30% Half-elf, 10% Elf, 5% other races)<br>Government: Lord Conrad Pixton (Human Male) works alongside Overseer Dara Erneth (Elf Female) to keep the town profitable and orderly.<br>Defense: The town boasts a white stone brick palisade that surrounds it. This protects mostly against the various monsters that live in the surrounding forest. Most of the town guards are only part-time guards employed by the Overseer. The part-time guards are often monster hunters who work as guards to generate a steadier income.<br>Commerce: Most basic goods and services are available here. Traders come from all across the empire to trade for and purchase exotic monster goods as well as more common monster goods from creatures that are bred here.<br>Organizations: There are temples and shrines to multiple gods in Holfirth, but the main god that is worshipped is Balinor. The Hunter's League employs a large number of townsfolk, along with the Beastkeep.<br>The land that Holfirth occupies was originally settled around 1450 PD and was named Holfirth in 1510 PD when the Larenthian Alliance incorporated it into the Federation. The name is derived from different words meaning forest. When the town was renamed upon incorporation, the natives described the location as Holt, meaning forest. So the new name became Holfirth, meaning "forest forest". The town is situated in the middle of the Shadowwood Forest on a large swath of land cleared from the forest next to a small lake. The lake is known as the Eldermere. Holfirth originated as a small trading post for hunters that operated in the Shadowwood Forest, and soon grew to be a booming central trade crossroads.<br><br>The Citadel: The Citadel is the walled in fortification at the center of the city. This is where Lord Pixton lives with the other nobles and the Overseer. The Lord's Keep is at the center of the Citadel and it is where the throne room is. The Daelonhart and Lorenskyr families also live within the Citadel. The guardians barracks is also in the citadel.<br>The Beast Market: Hundreds of market stalls are spread across an open town center. Here, any manner of beast goods can be purchased. Notable shops are the:<br>
<br>Ankheg Chitin stand (Owner Barnabus Tinkerfoot)
<br>Owlbear liver stand (Owner Lucinda Elnis)
<br>Crond stand (Owner Jeff)
<br>Basilisk poison stand (Owner Orin Ironhide)
<br>Artisan Alley: Shops here are all grouped together. All manner of smells and sounds mix in a cacophany.<br>Serum and Remedies<br>
- Owner: Jeetz - Jeetz is a 46 year old male lizardfolk brewer. He has a colorful frill and brown eyes. He has broad black scales. He stands 6'3" (192 cm) and has a fat build. He has an oval face.<br>The Chipped Pike<br>
- Owner: Hreda Metcalf - Hreda Metcalf is a 62 year old male human blacksmith. He has cropped, curled, white hair and brown eyes. He has rugged, golden skin. He stands 5'4" and has a beefy build. He has an oval face. He has broad shoulders. He has a slight lisp.<br>The Academic Weapon<br>
- Owner - Evel Dandridge - Evel Dandridge is a 47 year old female human scribe. She has long, wavy, black hair and blue eyes. She has rough, brown skin. She stands 5'1" (157 cm) and has a lean build. She has a square face. She twitches frequently from her left hand.<br>Shanna's Magical Trinkets<br>
- Owner - Shanna Ro - Shanna Ro is a short gnomish woman from Nrkamp. She is soft-spoken, yet very adamant about spreading the use of magic to everyone. She is about 4'0" and has a lean build. She has a soft, round face and pale skin.<br>The Arena Monstera: Fights are held here every few days where people can either volunteer or criminals are chosen to fight against beasts in epic battles. The fight arranger is named: Bennett Haldir. He is a very flamboyant human man who is always trying to make a deal.<br>The Sacred Ward: There are many temples and churches here to various gods.<br>
<br>The largest cathedral is dedicated to Balinor
<br>Others are dedicated to Cielia, <a data-href="Mortessa" href="http://wiki.alexsievert.com/argena/gods/mortessa.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Mortessa</a>, Lucite, Pholtus, Erathis, and Reicha
<br>Divinare Institute Campus: The Divinare Institute is headquartered in <a data-href="Wizendell" href="http://wiki.alexsievert.com/argena/chandaria/nations/larenthian-alliance/provinces/wizendell.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Wizendell</a>, but there is a satellite campus in Holfirth. The headmaster of the satellite is named Tos Agarvran<br>Tos: Tos Agarvran is a 96 year old female high elf wizard.&nbsp; She has short, curled, golden hair and brown eyes. She has rough, white skin. She stands 5'5" (167 cm) and has an skinny build. She has a soft face.<br>The head Librarian of the Institute is Adwear Boadle:<br>Adwear Boadle is a 62 year old male human historian. He has short, straight, blond hair and black eyes. He has dark skin. He stands 5'6" (169 cm) and has a skinny build. He has a square face. He smells heavily of unwashed clothes.]]></description><link>http://wiki.alexsievert.com/argena/chandaria/nations/larenthian-alliance/provinces/holfirth-province/holfirth.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Argena/Chandaria/Nations/Larenthian Alliance/Provinces/Holfirth Province/Holfirth.md</guid><pubDate>Thu, 25 Jan 2024 01:57:24 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Owlbear Enclave]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br>Mayor: Jiri Lanorys<br>
Overseer: Iolis Batira<br>Owlbear Enclave is built around a small babbling brook that runs from a spring in a nearby hillside. The brook is used for a few mills in town, as well as to drive machines that assist in the stripping of Owlbear pelts for feathers, and the harvesting of Owlbear talons. Master Harvester Bob&nbsp;Biggum&nbsp;extracts the livers of the harvested Owlbears. These are most often used in Alchemy, and such most are shipped off to&nbsp;<a data-href="Wizendell" href="http://wiki.alexsievert.com/argena/chandaria/nations/larenthian-alliance/provinces/wizendell.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Wizendell</a>. Most of the buildings in the village are built in a very medieval European style, but with many different colors, more like some Scandinavian towns. The mayor's name is Jiri&nbsp;Lanorys. She is a Tiefling from&nbsp;No'zaral. She came here because her family of scribes was disgraced and banished from the land for disobeying a noble's orders. She found her way here and soon became the mayor because of her learned nature. The overseer of the town is&nbsp;Iolis&nbsp;Batira, a half-elf man who is incredibly boring and mundane. He is just here to do his job and get paid, nothing else.<br>
Owlbear Enclave is home to quite a few colorful characters. Kram Bram, the local archaeologist in charge of Kram's Archaeology Shop, is an old man who is raring for an adventure. When given the opportunity to explore Helvalic Ruins, he jumps on board right away. Darryn Filoris is the antithesis to Kram. He is the very intelligent archivist at the Everwake Archives, he lacks all of Kram's ambition and gusto. Darryn would much rather spend his days inside reading with his cat Snookie.]]></description><link>http://wiki.alexsievert.com/argena/chandaria/nations/larenthian-alliance/provinces/holfirth-province/owlbear-enclave.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Argena/Chandaria/Nations/Larenthian Alliance/Provinces/Holfirth Province/Owlbear Enclave.md</guid><pubDate>Wed, 28 Feb 2024 05:50:15 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Timburg]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br>Timburg supplies all of the timber and basic building supplies for the Holfirth Province. The local archdruid oversees the harvesting of timber and ensures that the surrounding forest and wildlife do not suffer permanent damage from logging.]]></description><link>http://wiki.alexsievert.com/argena/chandaria/nations/larenthian-alliance/provinces/holfirth-province/timburg.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Argena/Chandaria/Nations/Larenthian Alliance/Provinces/Holfirth Province/Timburg.md</guid><pubDate>Wed, 28 Feb 2024 05:50:18 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Bippenbol]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br>Industrial city of gnomes, dwarves, and halflings.]]></description><link>http://wiki.alexsievert.com/argena/chandaria/nations/larenthian-alliance/provinces/bippenbol.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Argena/Chandaria/Nations/Larenthian Alliance/Provinces/Bippenbol.md</guid><pubDate>Mon, 22 Jan 2024 00:40:57 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Cabalman Run]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br>Town that specializes in breeding horses and training cavalrymen]]></description><link>http://wiki.alexsievert.com/argena/chandaria/nations/larenthian-alliance/provinces/cabalman-run.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Argena/Chandaria/Nations/Larenthian Alliance/Provinces/Cabalman Run.md</guid><pubDate>Wed, 28 Feb 2024 05:50:23 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Espwynstead]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br>Town that specializes in growing rare herbs and wines. Warm sea breeze blows across the landscape]]></description><link>http://wiki.alexsievert.com/argena/chandaria/nations/larenthian-alliance/provinces/espwynstead.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Argena/Chandaria/Nations/Larenthian Alliance/Provinces/Espwynstead.md</guid><pubDate>Fri, 16 Feb 2024 04:44:25 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Galvenport]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br>Population: 51,260 (37% humans, 14% elves, 21% half-elves, 11% gnomes, 9% halflings, 8% other races)<br>Government: Chief Magnate Thedric Alfir rules over the Larenthian Alliance from his throne here. He is known to be a slightly harsh but overall fair ruler. This city has a large amount of overseers, as well as apprentice overseers who train to be deployed to hamlets across the alliance. Chief Alfir consults with a council, known as the Mercantable, that consists of heads of industry from each major city in the alliance. These heads of industry reside mostly in Galvenport, so they have a tendency to be not very in-tune with the true needs of their represented people.<br>Defense: The capital city boasts a state of the art defensive system designed and built by the master inventors of <a data-href="Bippenbol" href="http://wiki.alexsievert.com/argena/chandaria/nations/larenthian-alliance/provinces/bippenbol.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Bippenbol</a>. The outer wall of the city is roughly 25 feet tall and made of large blocks of stone. Each tower along the wall has a catapult loaded with black powder bombs. Within the city, the Constabulary keeps the peace among the citizenry. Constables can be identified by the Galvenport insignia, a gold coin overlaid on a simple ship, embossed into their breastplate. The Chief Magnate employs his own noble guard.<br>Commerce: Nearly all goods are available in Galvenport, including illegal items. The underground market is sourced from a thriving smuggling empire on the sea. Contraband items include certain black powder devices, illegal magic items, and hallucinogenic substances.<br>Organizations: The Larenthian Trade Federation is headquartered in the city, and oversees all trade that happens in the Alliance. The <a data-href="#Underguild" href="http://wiki.alexsievert.com/about:blank#Underguild" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Underguild</a> runs the black market and all illegal activity in the city. The Divinaire Institute of <a data-href="Wizendell" href="http://wiki.alexsievert.com/argena/chandaria/nations/larenthian-alliance/provinces/wizendell.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Wizendell</a> also has a campus in the city and holds some sway in trading and politics.<br>Galvenport originated as a small seaside trading post run by the then merchant lord Lawrence Galaven. Over time, through clever business deals and a fortunate location on the coast, Galvenport grew to be an expansive and prosperous city. Once Galvenport had grown to considerable size, pirates and bandits started to become a serious problem. Pirates harassed merchant ships on the sea, and bandits attacked traders travelling over land. Galvenport was losing a lot of trade. It was at this point that Galaven realized he needed support in securing his lands. He reached out to the nearby large cities with a request for an alliance. Thus, the Larenthian Alliance was formed, mostly out of a need for security, and to grow the wealth of all the neighboring cities.<br>
Galvenport now has the most diverse available goods in the Alliance. All of the cities in the Alliance transport goods to Galvenport to have them sold to other nations. Merchant ships from many nations of Chandaria travel to Galvenport to trade exotic and illegal goods.<br>
The city itself is made of mostly stone brick and whitewashed wood buildings packed tightly together, funneling traders and consumers alike down crowded city streets. The center of the city, the Gilded Bastion, sits perched atop a low hill, making it such that the Harbor of Nations can be seen from most of the city. Separated from the rest of the bustling, crowded city streets, the richest of Galvenport live in the Windswept Gardens. Here in their large mansions and with lush trees and hedgerows, the upper class control the trade coming in and out of the city. In the Gilded Bastion, Alfir lives in and works from the Grand Keep. His council members also live in lavish mansions in the Bastion.<br>
Besides a large port and artisan district, Galvenport has many divine temples. Alfir has outlawed the worship of certain gods however, namely <a data-href="Asmodeus" href="http://wiki.alexsievert.com/argena/gods/asmodeus.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Asmodeus</a>, <a data-href="Tiamat" href="http://wiki.alexsievert.com/argena/gods/tiamat.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Tiamat</a>, <a data-href="Lolth" href="http://wiki.alexsievert.com/argena/gods/lolth.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Lolth</a>, <a data-href="Vecna" href="http://wiki.alexsievert.com/argena/gods/vecna.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Vecna</a>, and <a data-href="Harmonia" href="http://wiki.alexsievert.com/argena/gods/harmonia.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Harmonia</a>. All of the banned gods besides Harmonia are outlawed because they have been ruled as not conducive to prosperous trade. Worship of Harmonia is banned because of the <a data-href="Arcane Revolution" href="http://wiki.alexsievert.com/argena/chandaria/nations/larenthian-alliance/historical-events/arcane-revolution.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Arcane Revolution</a>.<br><br>The Chief and his family live in the Platinum Palace atop the Treska Plateau (named after Siegfried Treska, the third Chief Magnate of the Larenthian Alliance). The members of the Mercantable, who are also by far the richest denizens of Galvenport, live at the bottom of the Ascent in large, walled-in estates known as Golden Heights. Only members of these families or people with direct invitations from members of the Mercantable or the Chief can enter into Golden Heights through the gates. The members of the Mercantable are known to throw extremely lavish parties quite often, and other elite people that don't live within Golden Heights spend multiple nights a week boozing with the members of the Mercantable. It is rare for Alfir to join these parties, but he shows every once in a while to make his presence felt.<br>
Outside Golden Heights, the upper class lives in the Inner Locks. This is the largest enclosed district within the city. There are small shops and artisan buildings throughout the Locks, but it is mostly just living spaces.<br><br>Most people in the city either work at the port or in the <a data-href="#MoonCorp" href="http://wiki.alexsievert.com/about:blank#MoonCorp" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">MoonCorp</a>  factory. Most of the work done at the port is shipbuilding or cargo handling. People in the city are generally pretty happy with their lot in life. Work is fair and the pay is pretty good for most jobs. Galvenport has a bustling night life, for when people finish work for the day. Most folks flock to the city's various taverns, theaters, and even the city's own casino, The Jewel Casino.<br><br><br>MoonCorp is one of the largest employers in Galvenport. The company hires a lot of gnomes and dwarves to work in the factory in the north of the city. MoonCorp manufactures clockwork and arcane technologies for the Larenthian military. The MoonCorp compound is the most secure place in Galvenport besides the Platinum Palace.<br>
MoonCorp has expensive contracts with the Larenthian military. Besides that, they also do business with <a data-href="The Clockwork Consortium" href="http://wiki.alexsievert.com/argena/chandaria/organizations/the-clockwork-consortium.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">The Clockwork Consortium</a> and <a data-href="Valdens" href="http://wiki.alexsievert.com/argena/chandaria/nations/valdens/valdens.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Valdens</a>. <a data-href="The Clockwork Consortium" href="http://wiki.alexsievert.com/argena/chandaria/organizations/the-clockwork-consortium.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">The Clockwork Consortium</a> and MoonCorp deal in intellectual property more than physical trade. MoonCorp has a special private section of the port where they do all of their shipping out of.<br>
Most people in Galvenport don't necessarily like how much power MoonCorp has and how secretive the whole company is, but at the same time, they acknowledge that it is a necessary evil within the city because MoonCorp is one of the largest employers of Galvenport citizens and also brings in a ton of trade which boosts the economy of the city and the whole Alliance.<br>
The owner of MoonCorp is Geoffrey Ouesterling. He is one of the richest men in Galvenport and lives in Golden Heights despite not being a member of the Mercantable. He is a scrawny half-elf man with frizzy brown hair and glasses. He is around 5'10 and carries himself with an air of confidence. Despite being a very astute businessman, he can be very awkward sometimes.<br><br>Not many people know much about the Underguild. It is often a very ambiguous term that refers to most criminal activity in <a data-href="#Galvenport" href="http://wiki.alexsievert.com/about:blank#Galvenport" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Galvenport</a>. The actual Underguild is actually a very well-organized hierarchy of people whose lines of work don't fit too well with the law. Members of the Underguild  range from lowly thieves to bounty hunters and hitmen to heads of highly organized crime syndicate families. No matter their status, all members of the Underguild are bound by the Code. The Code only contains 3 rules. The first is that death is preferable to ratting on the Underguild. Anyone caught cooperating with authorities to sabotage the Underguild will be punished so severely they will wish they were dead. The second rule is that membership of the Underguild must be kept an utmost secret. Even close family members are not to know of one's membership with the guild. The last rule is that the Underguild is never to be cited as the source of a crime. No one committing a crime should openly claim allegiance to the Underguild or claim that the crime is a direct work of the Underguild.<br>
None of this information is known by the average person in Galvenport. Most people can only speculate about the Underguild. Being a member of it is generally seen as a bad thing because it means that person is an active criminal. <br><br>The Divinaire Institute of <a data-href="Wizendell" href="http://wiki.alexsievert.com/argena/chandaria/nations/larenthian-alliance/provinces/wizendell.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Wizendell</a> is based in <a data-href="Wizendell" href="http://wiki.alexsievert.com/argena/chandaria/nations/larenthian-alliance/provinces/wizendell.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Wizendell</a>. However, it has two other campuses outside of <a data-href="Wizendell" href="http://wiki.alexsievert.com/argena/chandaria/nations/larenthian-alliance/provinces/wizendell.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Wizendell</a>, one in Galvenport and one in <a data-href="Holfirth" href="http://wiki.alexsievert.com/argena/chandaria/nations/larenthian-alliance/provinces/holfirth-province/holfirth.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Holfirth</a>. Of the satellite campuses, the one in Galvenport is much larger. While the campus in Galvenport does educate many people in divination, it also serves as the Institute's center for political influence in the Alliance. The campus is located in the center for politics in the Alliance, making it much easier to assert influence in decisions.<br>
The Divinaire Campus in Galvenport also does most of the Institute's trading since much more trade in general goes through Galvenport. The Institute exports a lot of scrolls, books, and alchemical supplies. The alchemical supply shipments are especially guarded because the same supplies can also be used to make illegal drugs.<br>
The headmaster of the Galvenport is much more of a politician than an academic. ]]></description><link>http://wiki.alexsievert.com/argena/chandaria/nations/larenthian-alliance/provinces/galvenport.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Argena/Chandaria/Nations/Larenthian Alliance/Provinces/Galvenport.md</guid><pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 02:57:19 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Hullingsbrook]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br>A town not under the control of the Larenthian Federation. Thriving black market.]]></description><link>http://wiki.alexsievert.com/argena/chandaria/nations/larenthian-alliance/provinces/hullingsbrook.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Argena/Chandaria/Nations/Larenthian Alliance/Provinces/Hullingsbrook.md</guid><pubDate>Wed, 24 Jan 2024 20:59:50 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Luminespore Hollow]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br>Gnomish town that specializes in druidry. Centered around giant mushrooms that glow at night.]]></description><link>http://wiki.alexsievert.com/argena/chandaria/nations/larenthian-alliance/provinces/luminespore-hollow.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Argena/Chandaria/Nations/Larenthian Alliance/Provinces/Luminespore Hollow.md</guid><pubDate>Wed, 28 Feb 2024 05:50:37 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Orton]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br>Port town for mining goods.]]></description><link>http://wiki.alexsievert.com/argena/chandaria/nations/larenthian-alliance/provinces/orton.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Argena/Chandaria/Nations/Larenthian Alliance/Provinces/Orton.md</guid><pubDate>Wed, 28 Feb 2024 05:50:40 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Sylmin]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br>Mining town for silver from the mountains]]></description><link>http://wiki.alexsievert.com/argena/chandaria/nations/larenthian-alliance/provinces/sylmin.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Argena/Chandaria/Nations/Larenthian Alliance/Provinces/Sylmin.md</guid><pubDate>Sat, 20 Jan 2024 19:30:53 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Wizendell]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br>Town that specializes in arcane knowledge and resources]]></description><link>http://wiki.alexsievert.com/argena/chandaria/nations/larenthian-alliance/provinces/wizendell.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Argena/Chandaria/Nations/Larenthian Alliance/Provinces/Wizendell.md</guid><pubDate>Sat, 20 Jan 2024 19:30:49 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Blurn's Rest]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br>Blurn's Rest is a trading hub and rest stop for merchant caravans travelling between cities in the <a class="internal-link" data-href="The Larenthian Alliance.md" href="http://wiki.alexsievert.com/argena/chandaria/nations/larenthian-alliance/the-larenthian-alliance.html" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Larenthian Alliance</a>. It sits at the Four Corners Crossroads in between <a data-href="Galvenport" href="http://wiki.alexsievert.com/argena/chandaria/nations/larenthian-alliance/provinces/galvenport.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Galvenport</a> and <a data-href="Holfirth" href="http://wiki.alexsievert.com/argena/chandaria/nations/larenthian-alliance/provinces/holfirth-province/holfirth.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Holfirth</a>. The owner, a large friendly Firbolg named Blurn, mans a tavern and inn named Blurn's Cairn. The main feature of the tavern is a tower of large stones that rises through the center of the building, making it visible for many miles around. Besides Blurn's Cairn, Blurn's Rest has a few market stalls where merchants and local farmers sell goods to travelers. There are also many tents set up where people rest while travelling.]]></description><link>http://wiki.alexsievert.com/argena/chandaria/nations/larenthian-alliance/blurn's-rest.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Argena/Chandaria/Nations/Larenthian Alliance/Blurn's Rest.md</guid><pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 02:57:19 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Sir Josiah Trembleton's Funhaus]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br>This travelling circus travels all across the Alliance, performing at various hubs of activities. Their most famous performance is at the Soltide Festival in <a data-href="Galvenport" href="http://wiki.alexsievert.com/argena/chandaria/nations/larenthian-alliance/provinces/galvenport.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Galvenport</a> each year. They also spend a few months at <a data-href="Blurn's Rest" href="http://wiki.alexsievert.com/argena/chandaria/nations/larenthian-alliance/blurn's-rest.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Blurn's Rest</a> each summer.]]></description><link>http://wiki.alexsievert.com/argena/chandaria/nations/larenthian-alliance/sir-josiah-trembleton's-funhaus.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Argena/Chandaria/Nations/Larenthian Alliance/Sir Josiah Trembleton's Funhaus.md</guid><pubDate>Fri, 16 Feb 2024 23:30:56 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[The Larenthian Alliance]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br>Capital City: Galvenport<br>The Larenthian Alliance was formed around 1000 years ago in the year 1508 PS by the merchant lord turned ruler, Chief Magnate Lawrence Galaven. The Alliance started out as mainly a trade alliance between the local towns. Over time it transformed into a political alliance as well. In the modern day, the cities are all very closely knit politically, but the cities are each entitled to enforce their own laws as well. The Larenthian Federation is the political body that governs the united cities. The current Chief Magnate is Thedric Alfir. The Chief Magnate is often referred to as just "The Chief", or "Chief Alfir". Alfir is a harsh but fair ruler. He values order above all else. Justice is swift but not overreaching. Laws are enforced by the Overseers. There are a few Overseers per town that coordinate the enforcement of Federal laws. The Overseers work with the town guards to enforce both Local and Federal laws. The Larenthian Federation doesn't provide any basic guards to the cities, it only provides Overseers. The capital of the Alliance is Galvenport. The Federation has its headquarters there, and the Chief Magnate lives there as well. The power of the Federation does not go unquestioned however. Cities in the past have attempted to rise up and leave the Federation, but heavy trade embargos swiftly reign them back in to the Alliance.<br>The Larenthian Alliance is bordered on the East by the Northern branch of the Twin Straits. To the south the border is defined by the edge of the Eternal Scorch. To the west is the Martyr's Summits.<br><br>The goals of the Larenthian Alliance are quite simple. Since its inception, the Alliance has stood on the grounds of accumulating as much wealth as possible. The initial allying of the cities of Larenthia in 1508 PS was the last time that the borders of the Alliance were expanded. The Larenthian Alliance has never fought in an offensive war in all its time, and has relied solely on fortifications on its borders and defensive prowess to win the conflicts it has been involved in. Because of this history, another goal that much of the government agrees on is by funding the development of military defenses on the borders.<br>
There is a sect of the government that has grown more powerful in recent times that advocates for increasing the power of the Larenthian Federation, and making the cities of the Alliance more alike and connected. This would give more power to the government through being able to closely affect the laws and trade in the cities. The opposing faction in the government counters with saying that this would be taking freedom away from the cities and undermining what makes the heart of the Alliance. <br><br>The Larenthian Alliance tries to maintain cordial relations with all the other nations of Chandaria because its good for trade and business. However, this leads to most of the other nations seeing the Alliance as somewhat of pushovers, and they have been often targeted in past wars. There have been two major wars in the Alliance's lifespan. The first war, The Omen War, between the Alliance and the former nation of Stormion. This war ended in a stalemate, not leading to any significant gains in territory for either side. This war is of little importance now since Falstor took over all of Stormion's land. However, were the Stormion loyalists to return to power, they might go after the Alliance next. The other significant war was with Norlund. This is known as the War of Scorched Earth. This war happened in 2357 PS, and resulted in a 50 year occupation of the Espwynstead Province. Eventually through diplomacy and trade embargos, the Alliance was able to reclaim the region, and focus on reinforcing the coastal border. Other than these two wars, there are often small raids from the people of Norlund to raze the villages in the Espwynstead province and steal food, cattle, and gold.<br>
The Alliance otherwise maintains very strong relations with the other nations of Chandaria. They are especially tightly allied with Valdens, as Wizendell and Spellhaven share a ton of arcane knowledge as it relates to divination.<br>
In terms of intranational relationships, most citizens of the Alliance dislike the federation in general, because of the bureaucratic laws that are put on the people, and because of the taxes that the federation takes from local businesses. However, they do acknowledge that the Alliance does provide a comfortable life for most people within.<br>
Chief Alfir, being the ruler of the Alliance, is not allowed to sit on the Federation board, but members of his council are, and he has very good relations with the Federation regardless, because of the heavy dues that it pays to the Chief's coffers.<br><br><br>Chief Alfir is in his third decade being the ruler of Larenthia. While the Alliance doesn't have a bloodline succession, the children of Chief's often have an increased chance of becoming Chiefs themselves. Alfir's father was not a Chief himself, but was a very prominent merchant in Galvenport, and sat on the Federation board in his later years. Alfir is 67 years old, and currently trying to leverage his power to get his son, Godfrey Alfir, to become the next Chief, but the Federation board is not huge fans of having another Alfir in power. Thedric is well respected by his council, as well as by most members of the Federation board. He is also fairly well-liked by citizens of the Alliance, but is not without his dissenters, who are often people wanting to overthrow the Federation as a whole.<br><br>While "prince" is not an official title, many people in the Alliance call Godfrey the Prince because of how his father, Chief Alfir, is trying to establish a blood succession for the throne. Godfrey is very adamant on taking the throne once his father dies or relinquishes it. He is trying to get all of the Council to like him, but is finding it harder than he originally thought, as everyone's opinion on a familial succession overpowers whatever opinion they may have about him as a person.<br>
Godfrey is currently 23 years old and spends most of his time partying, hunting, and sparring. When he's not doing one of these things, he is unsuccessfully trying to gain influence in the Council.<br><br>Councilman Shaffer sits on the Chief's council and is a pretty trusted and well-respected member. He also holds the position of Treasurer of the Larenthian Federation. The treasurer position is responsible for handling taxes and deciding where funds are sent once collected. Shaffer works very closely with the Overseer Supreme to coordinate tax and fine collection from all of the cities, towns, and villages of the Alliance. Shaffer is known to be a little hot-headed sometimes, and can make some rash decisions.<br><br>The Lawbringers have been the heads of the overseers for multiple generations now. Helga also sits on the Chief's council. Helga is very lazy at her job because of how long her family has held the position and how secure her job is because of that. She coordinates with the Overseers below her, who themselves are each responsible for one of the major cities. Helga is not super fond of Chief Alfir, but keeps a working relationship with him.<br><br>Dormar is a half-elf who is the Head Diviner of the Alliance. He also serves as the headmaster of the Divinaire Institute at <a data-href="Wizendell" href="http://wiki.alexsievert.com/argena/chandaria/nations/larenthian-alliance/provinces/wizendell.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Wizendell</a>. He travels between the two places very often and is very involved at both. When there are decisions that concern Wizendell versus the Alliance, he tends to side with Wizendell. Dormar is a patient and generally well-liked man. He is just as much of an intellectual, as he is a politician.]]></description><link>http://wiki.alexsievert.com/argena/chandaria/nations/larenthian-alliance/the-larenthian-alliance.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Argena/Chandaria/Nations/Larenthian Alliance/The Larenthian Alliance.md</guid><pubDate>Wed, 24 Jan 2024 06:32:32 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Kul-Radein]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br>]]></description><link>http://wiki.alexsievert.com/argena/chandaria/nations/no'zaral/kul-radein.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Argena/Chandaria/Nations/No'zaral/Kul-Radein.md</guid><pubDate>Thu, 29 Feb 2024 17:20:21 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[No'zaral]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br>Capital City: Jequith<br>The capital city of Jequith sits in Umeqen's Bay, north of the mouth of the Ichor River that flows down from the Exalted Summit.]]></description><link>http://wiki.alexsievert.com/argena/chandaria/nations/no'zaral/no'zaral.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Argena/Chandaria/Nations/No'zaral/No'zaral.md</guid><pubDate>Thu, 29 Feb 2024 17:18:27 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Welbenwallow]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br>Welbenwallow is a gnomish city that is essentially run by <a data-href="The Clockwork Consortium" href="http://wiki.alexsievert.com/argena/chandaria/organizations/the-clockwork-consortium.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">The Clockwork Consortium</a>.]]></description><link>http://wiki.alexsievert.com/argena/chandaria/nations/no'zaral/welbenwallow.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Argena/Chandaria/Nations/No'zaral/Welbenwallow.md</guid><pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 02:57:19 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Berserker's Rest]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br>The capital city of Norlund, Berserker's Rest sits on the Stalwart River, north of the Champion's Range. The river allows the city to trade with the other towns and villages of Norlund. <br>The ruling government of Norlund is based in Berserker's Rest, but it is a loose binding. Norlund is ruled by the strongest warrior clan heads in the land, and they usually don't favor living in the capital. ]]></description><link>http://wiki.alexsievert.com/argena/chandaria/nations/norlund/berserker's-rest.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Argena/Chandaria/Nations/Norlund/Berserker's Rest.md</guid><pubDate>Sun, 16 Jun 2024 02:15:07 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Frostgate]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br><br>The population of Frostgate is 21,345 (51% Humans, 29% Dwarves, 13% Elves, 7% Other)<br><br>Like all other cities in Norlund, Frostgate is ruled by it's Chieftain. However, the Chieftain of Frostgate holds additional responsibilities, as the Chieftain also holds the title of Riftkeeper. The Riftkeeper is in charge of keeping the Frostfire Engine burning.<br>The Chieftain must constantly fight to keep the position. The only way to stake an official claim to the position is through combat. Anyone who has killed another in a battle and whose family owns land is able to challenge the Chieftain to combat.<br><br>Frostgate sits behind a wooden palisade that was constructed during the Arcane Resurgence when the city was first founded. The wall is made of Elderbark, and it's said the magic of the trees make the wood more resilient than stone. <br>In addition to the wall, every citizen in Frostgate is ready to take up arms at a moment's notice, willing to give their lives to defend the city from outside invaders from their own plane, or that beyond the gate.<br><br>Like most cities in Norlund, Frostgate has very little contact with the world beyond Norlund. Many exotic goods are not available in the city, and the city's markets consist of mostly local goods.<br><br><br>The Mages of Fire are the people in charge of managing the actual melting down of magical items in the Engine. They are masters in the Ritual of Flame, the complicated rite of ensuring that the magic of the artifacts is correctly harnessed by the Engine. Out in public, members of the Mages of Fire are extremely easy to spot, sporting bright red incandescent robes that seem to shimmer like embers in the sun.<br><br>The Crystal Archivists maintain the Crystal Archives, Norlund's largest collection of arcane knowledge. The Crystal Archives are carved out of a massive ice crystal cavern beneath the city. The job of the Archivists is to take notes on every single magic item that is melted in the Frostfire Engine. The Crystal Archives are heavily guarded, as it contains nearly 2,000 years of magical item blueprints.<br><br>The Snowstalkers are masters of the wild tundra. It is their duty to scour the wilderness for magical items and artifacts to fuel the Frostfire Engine. They are rangers, scouts, and druids alike, all masters of traveling and surviving the harsh wastes of the north.<br><br>The Cryomancer's Cult is a group dedicated to reopening the portal to the Frostfell and embracing it's power. They believe that the Frostfell could be tamed, it's power harnessed to control a kingdom. Members of the cult embrace all things cold and ice, and they renounce the Ritual of Flame.<br><br>During the Arcane Resurgence, overambitious mages opened a portal to the Frostfell and were consequently destroyed. The portal remained, and it took a great group of heroes to regain control of the gate and subdue its power. The portal created by the initial Frost Mages couldn't be permanently closed because the tear in the Interplanar Fabric was too large and there was too much energy leaking through the rift, but they were able to create a device called the Frostfire Engine, to emit its own energy and balance out the instability of the rift, keeping it closed as long as the Engine had magical energy. The magical energy needed to be derived from melted down magic items, and thus the Mages of Fire were founded. They remain to this day the keepers of the Engine.]]></description><link>http://wiki.alexsievert.com/argena/chandaria/nations/norlund/frostgate.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Argena/Chandaria/Nations/Norlund/Frostgate.md</guid><pubDate>Sun, 23 Jun 2024 23:58:52 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Isbre]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br>Isbre is the most fortified place in Norlund. Built into the side of a massive glacier, the city's streets wind through the layers of ice and packed snow. Many of the nation's military might is stationed in Isbre, since it is so fortified. ]]></description><link>http://wiki.alexsievert.com/argena/chandaria/nations/norlund/isbre.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Argena/Chandaria/Nations/Norlund/Isbre.md</guid><pubDate>Sun, 16 Jun 2024 01:47:50 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Lahab's Embrace]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br>Located in the north of The Spine, Lahab's Embrace sits nestled between two mountain peaks, looking over the Azure Expanse to the north. People from all over Norlund flock to Lahab's Embrace, as it is the premiere place for viewing the Aurora's that form over the Northern Expanse. <br>The town derives its name from Lahab, the Father of Fire Elementals, for whom it is said heats the town. All over it there are hot springs, which are said to be portals to the Plane of Fire. Locals thank Lahab for the heat provided by the springs.]]></description><link>http://wiki.alexsievert.com/argena/chandaria/nations/norlund/lahab's-embrace.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Argena/Chandaria/Nations/Norlund/Lahab's Embrace.md</guid><pubDate>Sun, 16 Jun 2024 01:11:57 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Lyntrn]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br>Lyntrn is a city located high in the summits of the Spine. It sits atop the Thundering Peak, a mountaintop that is constantly surrounded by a roiling lightning storm. The city is home to a thriving artificer's guild, who draw on the power of the storm through their Stormcatcher Towers. These towers harness the power of the lightning strikes to power the city's arcane technology.]]></description><link>http://wiki.alexsievert.com/argena/chandaria/nations/norlund/lyntrn.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Argena/Chandaria/Nations/Norlund/Lyntrn.md</guid><pubDate>Sun, 16 Jun 2024 00:02:26 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Norlund]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br>Capital City: Berserker's Rest<br>Berserker's Rest is built on the banks of the Stalwart River, which flows down from the Champion's Range. The river continues out to the nearby bay to the east, where merchant ships travel through to get to Berserker's Rest.]]></description><link>http://wiki.alexsievert.com/argena/chandaria/nations/norlund/norlund.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Argena/Chandaria/Nations/Norlund/Norlund.md</guid><pubDate>Mon, 22 Jan 2024 00:41:03 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Vulfen]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br><br>The population of Vulfen is 32,367 (41% Elves, 35% Humans, 20% Dire Wolves (Shtor), 4% Other)<br><br>Vulfen's government is slightly different than the rest of the cities of Norlund, it has two rulers instead of one. One of them, the Chieftain, rules over the humanoids of the city. The other, the Beastspeaker, maintains control over the sentient Dire Wolves, known as the Shtor, and shifters of the city. The Beastspeaker's job is by far harder than the Chieftain's, as the Beastspeaker is charged with maintaining the delicate relationship between the sentient Dire Wolves and the bestial Dire Wolves, simply known as bestials, that are bred for the army.<br><br>The defense of Vulfen relies solely on the wolves raised there. The city has no walls, but instead has open fields that surround the city, allowing the dire wolves to attack at full capacity during a siege.<br><br>The Vulpine Market at the center of Vulfen is the center of a vast trade network that runs throughout eastern Norlund. Other than Dire Wolves, Vulfen has no other major exports. However, it does have access to some exotic imported goods that are delivered by the merchants that come to pick up Dire Wolves.<br>Vulfen is also known for Gyldmen Heights, a neighborhood of large manors belonging to the richest merchants in the city. Gyldmen Heights sits built on the side of a large hill on the western edge of the city. <br><br><br>Because of all the werewolves that prowl the Vulfenwood, silver working is a very prominent skill. Every town, village, and hamlet in or near the Vulfenwood needs silvered weapons to defend themselves. The Silversmiths are similar to a guild and they operate out of Vulfen. Their primary concern is keeping the price of silver reasonable and making sure that every Silversmith in the province has enough supply.<br><br>The Breeder's Guild concerns themselves mostly with the production of bestial Dire Wolves. They ensure that the breeding is done ethically and they manage the trading of the bestials to other cities. This guild is often under scrutiny from some Shtor that believe that all Dire Wolves should be treated equal.<br><br>The Moonlight Mercenaries are a very decentralized organization of adventurers, fighters, and rangers that patrol the Vulfenwood and protect the passing travelers. The Chieftain of Vulfen is responsible for allocating funds to the mercenaries, as they don't take payment from those they protect. Some mercenaries are also available in Vulfen to be hired to protect travelers on their way out.<br><br>The Cult of Balinor operates within Vulfen. They are dedicated to preserving the sanctity of the hunt, and ensuring fair living conditions for all beasts. They are firmly against the breeding of bestials in Vulfen. They believe that every creature should have the opportunity to fight for its own freedom during a hunt.<br><br>Vulfen was founded as a sanctuary within the Vulfenwood. The local villagers within the forest were being overrun by werewolves. A small group of them eventually found sanctuary with some sentient Dire Wolves they found living out of a small cave den. They were shocked by the civility of these Wolves, and they eventually learned to live together, creating a safe haven in the middle of the Vulfenwood.<br>As Vulfen grew bigger, they needed a way to gain money. The original Shtor, who looked down on the bestial Dire Wolves, proposed the taming and selling of bestials for war. This turned out to be an insanely profitable business.]]></description><link>http://wiki.alexsievert.com/argena/chandaria/nations/norlund/vulfen.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Argena/Chandaria/Nations/Norlund/Vulfen.md</guid><pubDate>Sun, 30 Jun 2024 22:32:06 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Rhugnurt]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br>]]></description><link>http://wiki.alexsievert.com/argena/chandaria/nations/rodigia/rhugnurt.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Argena/Chandaria/Nations/Rodigia/Rhugnurt.md</guid><pubDate>Tue, 09 Jul 2024 22:17:15 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Rodigia]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br>Capital City: Rhugnurt<br>Prior to the Kingdom's founding, the area of Rodigia was a smattering of steadings of Giants that had inhabited the land for thousands of years. During this time, the land was called Jotunstll. Many of the families of Jotunstll claim descendance from Annam the Progenitor or his offspring.<br>The Kingdom of Rodigia was founded in 190 PS, following the <a class="internal-link" data-href="An Overall History Of Chandaria" href="http://wiki.alexsievert.com/argena/chandaria/chandarian-history/an-overall-history-of-chandaria.html" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Rending of Skies</a>. The Kingdom was founded because an extremely powerful Storm Giant by the name of Stronmar, who at the time was living alone atop Mount Thogrin, was able to channel enough of his own tempestuous power to dispel Thalroth's storm over Jotunstll. Stronmar claimed that his power came from his bloodline which was descended directly from Stronmaus himself. Stronmar used this victory and his lineage to declare himself at the top of the Ordning. All of the giants living in Jotunstll were awestricken by Stronmar's power, and they rallied behind him, fearing a retaliatory attack from Thalroth. Thus, the Kingdom of Rodigia was founded (Stronmar renamed the land to cement his legacy), with Stronmar as the first Mountain King.<br><br>The current Mountain King of Rodigia is a Storm Giant named Strullar Anling.]]></description><link>http://wiki.alexsievert.com/argena/chandaria/nations/rodigia/rodigia.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Argena/Chandaria/Nations/Rodigia/Rodigia.md</guid><pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2024 17:55:58 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Dormuntirth's Lair]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br>During the <a data-href="Age of Dragons" href="http://wiki.alexsievert.com/Age of Dragons" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Age of Dragons</a>, an adult blue dragon named Dormuntirth made the Oasis its lair. The legend goes that Dormuntirth kept his treasure hoard submerged in the water of the Oasis. The dragon raided the local tribes and also some of the Scorch's dissension ruins from the Battle of the Planes. He amassed a sizable fortune of gold, gems, and magic items.<br>
At the height of his power, Dormuntirth's territory spanned for a hundred miles out from the Oasis. Multiple tribes were paying him tribute, and he was collecting treasures from adventurers passing through his territory.<br>
After his raiding caught enough attention, a group of adventurers from present-day <a data-href="Norlund" href="http://wiki.alexsievert.com/argena/chandaria/nations/norlund/norlund.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Norlund</a> slew Dormuntirth and claimed his treasure hoard for themselves. However, it's said that some of Dormuntirth's treasure was left behind and remains buried at the bottom of the Water of Life. ]]></description><link>http://wiki.alexsievert.com/argena/chandaria/nations/the-eternal-scorch/history/dormuntirth's-lair.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Argena/Chandaria/Nations/The Eternal Scorch/History/Dormuntirth's Lair.md</guid><pubDate>Thu, 25 Apr 2024 05:16:15 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[The Skrekin People]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br>The Skrekin People were a goblinoid culture that were the first permanent inhabitants of the central oasis of the desert. The beginning of their habitation marks the start of the Wahatan Era. This Era began in 2308 PS and lasted up until the Kha'anj invasion in 2451 PS.<br><br>The first permanent settlement of the oasis was constructed in 2308 PS by the Skrekin Alliance. It  was very small, consisting almost entirely of small wood and clay hovels. The Skrekin called their settlement Skrei, naming it after themselves. Skrekin culture was incredibly accepting and adaptable, and consequently it evolved rapidly. The Skrekin assimilated many different groups of people into their culture, and expanded Skrei to fit. The village doubled in size in the first 5 years, and doubled again by the turn of the first decade.<br><br>Skrei had quadrupled in size after only a decade, and Skrekin culture had evolved just as much. What had initially formed as a society focused solely on gathering enough food to survive day-to-day, became an advanced society focused on scientific, philosophical, theological, and technological discovery. With the growing aggregation of knowledge from across Chandaria, the need arose for a place to store all of it. This is what prompted the beginning of construction on the Library of Skrei. The construction finished in 2320 PS, and the Library of Skrei became the largest collection of knowledge and texts outside of the Sanctum Arcana in Spellhaven. Historians consider the end of construction on the Library of Skrei to be the beginning of what they call The Wahatan Enlightenment. For the next century, Skrei saw progress like no city before it. The Library of Skrei continued to expand its collection and became the driving force of innovation. Any text that travelers had was taken to the Library and copied by the master scribes and given back. Scholars started traveling from across the continent to peruse the Library's collections. During the Wahatan Enlightenment, Skrei, which had once occupied a small amount of the Oasis's shore, expanded to encompass the entire Oasis, and the population grew exponentially as Skrei became the most luxurious place to live in the desert.<br><br>One of the most prevalent inventions from the Wahatan Enlightenment Period is the modern sand skiff, known as a Sandsail. The Sandsail was created in 2343 PS by a collective of goblin inventors drawing on tram technology from Bippenbol and naval technologies from the Atrisean Dynasty. Sandsails are usually made of wood with a sail made from giant snake skin. Sandsails are still in use today, but they are banned from Kha'anj and the surrounding area.<br>
The second major invention of the Wahatan Enlightenment was the Skrekin Calendar. For all of  recorded history, time has been documented via the Celestial Calendar (once called the Anteitic Calendar). The Celestial Calendar is based on the solstices and equinoxes, with the months divided evenly between them. The Skrekin people found this calendar to be inefficient, with its multiple holidays separate from the actual months, and the ten-day division of months inauspicious for good work week balance. They came up with the Skrekin Calendar, which instead is 13 months that are 28 days each. They kept Deepwinter separate from the other months still, since it wasn't based around the seasonal changes. They called the thirteenth month Skreitan, and it fit in between Messime and Planimor in the Celestial Calendar, with all the other months the same.<br>
The Skrekin Calendar never caught on, but some scholars still argue for its adoption over the Celestial Calendar.<br><br>In the 10 years leading up to 2451 PS, the Kha'anj coalition gained influence and power across the central Scorch. The coalition was made up of the most brutal, power-hungry warlords and they all banded together under the mission of claiming the peaceful civilization of Skrei for them themselves. The Kha'anj invasion lasted for only 5 days, and was one of the shortest sieges Chandaria had ever seen.<br>
The lack of defenses around Skrei, and the clear mismatch in combat superiority between the two cultures led to quick and brutally efficient fighting. During the sacking of the city, the Kha'anj burned the Library of Skrei, as it represented the heart of Skrekin civilization. They killed indiscriminately, and the Skrekin either had to flee or try to fight back.<br>
Most of Skrei was rebuilt and expanded by the Kha'anj, who renamed the oasis to the Kha'anj Oasis. The Kha'anj civilization that replaced the Skrekin couldn't have been more different. Harsh, oligarchic governance took over streets that once housed some of the continent's greatest thinkers and peacemakers.]]></description><link>http://wiki.alexsievert.com/argena/chandaria/nations/the-eternal-scorch/history/the-skrekin-people.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Argena/Chandaria/Nations/The Eternal Scorch/History/The Skrekin People.md</guid><pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2024 05:52:22 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Kha'anj]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br>Population: 10,256 (89% Goblinoids, 5% Humans, 5% Tieflings, 1% Other)<br>Government: An oligarchy known as the Sayid Alma runs the oasis. There are 4 Sayids that make up the Sayid Alma. They enforce their strict policies via the Ma'himat, the city guards. The Sayid Alma mostly deals with issues of trade and punishment. The capitol building of Kha'anj is called the Castle of Brass. It is in the middle of the oasis, overlooking the main body of water, the Water of Life (Ma' Alhaya).<br>Defense: The city has no structural defenses. The main roads into it are patrolled by guards (Ma'himat), and a contingent of Ma'himat also patrol the outer edges of the city. Within the city, each of the Sayids has a large, fortified estate. They all boast impressive walls, defensive siege weaponry, and dedicated private security forces.<br>Commerce: The Kha'anj Oasis suffers from its location in the middle of a desert, so most goods available in the city are not from local sources. Instead, the city thrives on exotic goods delivered via merchant caravans making a stop while on their journeys through the desert. Most common goods are readily available, but higher end exotic goods are usually in rare supply.<br>Organizations: The Sayid Alma controls all facets of life within the city, from trade to religion to education. There are people living in the Oasis today who were either around during the Wahatan Era, or wish to return to a Skrekin societal model. This group is called the Skrekin Traditionalists. The goal of their movement is to overthrow the Sayid Alma and reinstitute the Skrekin way of life in the Oasis.<br>Tales have been passed down through generations in the Scorch about the great oasis at its center. There are many different ideas about its origin, but the most prevalent theory is that thousands of years ago during the <a class="internal-link" data-href="The Great Dissension.md" href="http://wiki.alexsievert.com/argena/chandaria/chandarian-history/the-great-dissension.html" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Battle of the Planes</a>, the goddess Libai was engaged in battle with the Ancient Archmages, and her hand was separated from her arm by an assailant. The hand fell to the ground and from it, the Oasis blossomed. Many theorize that the Water of Life, or Ma'Alhaya to the locals, is the blood of Libai that then pooled from the dismembered hand.<br>
The Oasis sat mostly untouched for over two millennia after the Scourge, with travelers only ever briefly stopping by on their way through the Scorch. Permanent settlement began in 2308 PS, when a small tribal alliance of goblinoids known as the Skrekin Alliance made their home around the Oasis and constructed a small village. The period in which the Skrekin people inhabited the Oasis is known as the Wahatan Era. "Wahatan" comes from the name given to the Oasis by the Skrekin people. These people were very open to outsiders and passing travelers and consequently, their culture evolved very rapidly. Science and technology thrived in the area, and a prosperous, open-minded society emerged.<br>
This society lasted for around a century, until a much larger coalition of Scorch inhabitants besieged the settlement and claimed it as their own. This coalition was known as the Kha'anj, and it was made of the Scorch's most power-hungry, ruthless warlords. They renamed the Wahatan Oasis to the Kha'anj Oasis to serve as a constant reminder of their power over the Oasis and its water. The leaders of this coalition went on to establish the Sayid Alma, and their families became the first of the Water Children, the upper elite class in the Flow Caste System. Much of the architecture in the Kha'anj oasis today is inspired by that of the Wahatan Era, while some of the more grand buildings were left unchanged and instead were repurposed by the Sayid Alma.<br><br>Water is the most valuable resource in the Scorch. It is incredibly rare and heavily regulated and guarded. The majority of citizens get their water from small wells around the city. The only people who don't are the Water Children. This is the highest level of the Flow Caste System. The people in this level are the Sayid Alma and their families. These people live in walled off compounds within the city and have their own sources of water inside.<br>
The Flow Caste System consists of 4 levels, each corresponding to the amount of water that people are allotted. The highest level is the Water Children. They are granted as much water as they would like. The next level down is the Respectables. This caste is larger than the Water Children and is made up of respected artisans, merchants, and guildsmen. These people are allotted 45 cups per day for their family, a healthy amount. The next level down is called the Commons and is the largest group. The people here are mostly general laborers. They are allotted 30 cups per day for their family. The lowest level is the Unmentionables. These people are the poorest in the city. They are persecuted by the Sayid Alma and are forced out of the public eye. They are only allotted 15 cups of water per day for their family. Visitors rarely see any members of the Unmentionables when traveling through the city because the Sayid Alma tries to sequester them to parts of the city where no one goes.<br>
Everyone is forbidden from drinking from the Water of Life. It is the most heavily guarded part of the city. Only the 4 Sayid Alma, and the state-appointed cleric of Libai are allowed to interact with the water.<br><br>Worship of all gods is prohibited except for Maglubiyet and Libai (in a limited capacity). Worship of every kind was allowed during the Wahatan Era, and the Kha'anj banned worship of all gods to exert their power over the city. Maglubiyet remained because outlawing him would have driven most goblins away from the Oasis forever.<br>
Worship of Libai is allowed but only in a limited capacity. Libai is regarded by most as the patron goddess of the Oasis, and most that live in Kha'anj feel some sense of reverence for her because she supplies them with water. However, no one is allowed to become a cleric of Libai, except for the single state-appointed cleric. This is because the Sayid Alma fear that clerics of Libai could create their own water and overthrow their government. This ban is enforced strictly and the punishment is death.<br><br>There are 4 Sayid Alma, each control a quarter of the city. The eastern Sayid is Rogdos Nugru. She is a very buff goblin who is known to be harsh but mostly fair. The northern Sayid is Zuzran the Coward. He is a skinny hobgoblin who no one ever sees much of and is a pushover when it comes to anything to do with politics. The western Sayid is Jerg Jag. He is a short obese goblin who shelters unmentionables within his walled off estate. The southern Sayid is Odrokos Maul. He is a very tall hobgoblin that is by far the most tyrannical of all the Sayids.]]></description><link>http://wiki.alexsievert.com/argena/chandaria/nations/the-eternal-scorch/kha'anj.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Argena/Chandaria/Nations/The Eternal Scorch/Kha'anj.md</guid><pubDate>Sun, 16 Jun 2024 00:19:30 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[The Eternal Scorch]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br>The Eternal Scorch is a massive desert in the center of Chandaria. For the most part, it is totally inhospitable due to areas radiated by magic, completely barren sands, and brutal weather conditions. Despite this, many still call the Scorch home, from nomadic bandit tribes, to established aristocrats in the Kha'anj Oasis.<br>The Eternal Scorch used to go by a different name, the Opulent Steppe. Before the Scourge, the center of Chandaria was a rich grassland, teeming with life and full of fertile soil. This would all change in the final battle of the Scourge, the Battle of the Planes. During this battle, all the deities of both the upper and lower planes combined their power to banish the Ancient Archmages, ending the Scourge. However, this banishment unleashed an apocalyptic amount of magical energy, forever scarring the landscape.<br><br>At the center of the desert is a massive oasis. It was created during the Battle of the Planes when Libai's hand was severed by one of the Archmages, falling to the ground and fusing with the soil. The hand and the blood that pooled around it created the oasis.<br>The oasis is one of the only places where permanent settlement has been possible in the Eternal Scorch. It has been known by many names in the past. The Skrekin people called it the Wahatan Oasis, while the later Kha'anj Alliance would call it the Kha'anj Oasis.<br><br>East of the Eternal Scorch, the city of Jorfiin sits perched amongst the cliffs of Zay-Sakhar. A once prosperous city, it is now nothing more than a bed of debauchery, banditry, and crime.<br>In 2151 PS, several small tribes that had been fighting for control over the Zay-Sakhar cliffs struck up an economic alliance in the hopes of everyone profiting. They named their civilization Jorfiin. The basis of this alliance was the oil rich sands to the East, which they figured could make them extremely rich. They set up oil refineries and began their lamp oil business.<br>As the demand for lamp oil grew, Jorfiin grew as well. In the next few decades, the population grew to nearly 10,000. Jorfiin became the richest settlement in the Scorch, and outsiders began to grow jealous. In 2234 PS, a larger tribe known as the Kamin tribe assaulted the city. The battle however, was a slaughter for the Kamin tribe. As the attackers climbed the cliffs toward the city, the defenders let boulders loose that rolled down the cliffs decimated the attackers' ranks. After firing volleys of arrows at the remaining soldiers, the few surviving Kamin retreated. This military victory secured Jorfiin's control for years to come.<br>The Kamin tribe spent the next decades recouping and gaining more influence. In 2308 PS, they attacked again, this time with a much larger force, the Kamin Alliance. This time led by a goblin warlord by the name of Nabir Tak, the Kamin Alliance fought much smarter. They first attacked the oil refineries to the East. However, when they arrived, the entire oil field was completely abandoned, the oil wells completely dried up. They moved to attack the city, but it too was completely abandoned. It was as if everyone just left overnight. No one knows for sure where the original settlers went, but some tribes of the Kamin Alliance took over Jorfiin while others left and occupied the lands around the city. The tribes that settled to the west near the dried up oil fields named their settlement Aswadu, which would become the center of the Kamin Alliance.]]></description><link>http://wiki.alexsievert.com/argena/chandaria/nations/the-eternal-scorch/the-eternal-scorch.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Argena/Chandaria/Nations/The Eternal Scorch/The Eternal Scorch.md</guid><pubDate>Fri, 07 Jun 2024 02:30:29 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Spellhaven]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br>The population of Spellhaven is around 26,620 (29% Humans, 28% Elves, 22% Half-Elves, 14% Gnomes, 7% Other).<br><br>The governing body of <a data-href="Valdens" href="http://wiki.alexsievert.com/argena/chandaria/nations/valdens/valdens.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Valdens</a> rules from Spellhaven, and also acts as the city's government as well. The main body of the government is known as the Arcane Assembly. It is a collection of the nation's wisest mages, where right to rule is heavily based on meritocratic ideals. During proceedings, mages constantly try to outwit each other, often leading to legislation taking an extraordinary amount of time to pass.<br>Within the Arcane Assembly, the Octoclave is comprised of the eight most powerful mages, one from each school of magic. The Octoclave has the final say in disputed matters, although this is only if progress on an issue has reached a complete standstill, which almost never happens. Thus, the positions in the Octoclave are more symbolic than anything. The mages of the Octoclave are most often informally called the Deuces, which comes from the Octoclave's motto, duces inter pares (leaders among equals).<br><br>Since its creation during the <a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="An Overall History Of Chandaria > The Arcane Resurgence" data-href="An Overall History Of Chandaria#The Arcane Resurgence" href="http://wiki.alexsievert.com/argena/chandaria/chandarian-history/an-overall-history-of-chandaria.html#The_Arcane_Resurgence" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Arcane Resurgence</a>, Spellhaven has been known for its superior defensibility. The city is built like a multi-layered fortress. Large polished stone walls separate the city into districts, and each have large arcane cannons placed at intervals along the walls. The center of the city, the Volantrum, floats in the air above the rest of the city, kept afloat by an arcane engine somewhere in the depths of the Crystal Forum. Lining the edges of the Volantrum are even stronger arcane cannons. It's also said that the main spire of the Crystal Forum was once used as the focus of an extremely powerful evocation spell and could be used in the same way again if necessary.<br>Meanwhile, the Spellhaven Citizen's Militia of Mages, or SCMM (members are often referred to as "Skims"), keep the city safe from internal threats. The SCMM is comprised solely of ordinary citizens of the city who have undergone training in peacekeeping magic. They wear simple robes branded with the insignia of the militia on the back, a silver eight-pointed star surrounded by a thin gold band with runes inside. A midnight blue shield shape surrounds the emblem, completing the insignia. Wherever it is printed, the insignia seems to shimmer with soft silver light.<br><br>Spellhaven's main exports are not traditional trade goods, but rather knowledge. The city researches at a rate that is simply unproduceable by any other institution. Many of the research institutions in the city operate fervently under the <a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="The Kainomantic Principles" data-href="The Kainomantic Principles" href="http://wiki.alexsievert.com/argena/chandaria/chandarian-history/the-kainomantic-principles.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Kainomantic principles</a> that first allowed the city to flourish. Unbounded by strict research ethics, the city produces research that other institutions wouldn't even be allowed to. Most of the common research and knowledge of the city is available to everyone, but the more niche or risky the research is, the more it costs to access. The expensive knowledge is usually only available to longstanding partners of the city's research institutions anyways.<br><br>Spellhaven was built at the height of the <a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="An Overall History Of Chandaria > The Arcane Resurgence" data-href="An Overall History Of Chandaria#The Arcane Resurgence" href="http://wiki.alexsievert.com/argena/chandaria/chandarian-history/an-overall-history-of-chandaria.html#The_Arcane_Resurgence" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Arcane Resurgence</a> by a collective of <a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="The Kainomantic Principles" data-href="The Kainomantic Principles" href="http://wiki.alexsievert.com/argena/chandaria/chandarian-history/the-kainomantic-principles.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Kainomancers</a> who were looking for a place to build a city with magic at its core. They used conjuration and transmutation magic to raise the walls and buildings of the city from the ground, truly establishing the city's magical roots. The founders' original vision was to transform the entire island into a sprawling magical metropolis which would become the crown jewel of Chandaria. Their dream was never realized in their time, since the <a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="An Overall History Of Chandaria > The Astral Devastation" data-href="An Overall History Of Chandaria#The Astral Devastation" href="http://wiki.alexsievert.com/argena/chandaria/chandarian-history/an-overall-history-of-chandaria.html#The_Astral_Devastation" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Astral Devastation</a> that followed the <a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="An Overall History Of Chandaria > The Arcane Resurgence" data-href="An Overall History Of Chandaria#The Arcane Resurgence" href="http://wiki.alexsievert.com/argena/chandaria/chandarian-history/an-overall-history-of-chandaria.html#The_Arcane_Resurgence" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Arcane Resurgence</a> severely hindered the city's expansion for a long while.<br>The city would boom again during the Age of Dominion however, as it was the site of the Planar Nexus, which brought many incredibly intelligent mages to the city from across Argena. This was also the time that the 8 outer towns were built, and the Volantrum was first lifted. <br><br><br>All interplanar traffic leaving and entering Spellhaven usually goes through this Planar Nexus. The Nexus is a large pyramid-shaped building with an open interior and many openings in the stonework that lets in plenty of sunlight. The main attraction of the Nexus is a massive portal that leads to Sigil. This is usually considered the gateway to the rest of the multiverse. However, the Nexus also has smaller portals to planes that aren't easily accessed from the Outlands like the Feywild, Shadowfell, and the Elemental Planes.<br>The Lansen Memorial Planar Nexus is named after Godrick Lansen, the general from the <a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="An Overall History Of Chandaria > The Age of Dominion" data-href="An Overall History Of Chandaria#The Age of Dominion" href="http://wiki.alexsievert.com/argena/chandaria/chandarian-history/an-overall-history-of-chandaria.html#The_Age_of_Dominion" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Battle of Limmedorn's Rift</a> who pushed for Chandaria's expansion across the multiverse and began the <a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="An Overall History Of Chandaria > The Age of Dominion" data-href="An Overall History Of Chandaria#The Age of Dominion" href="http://wiki.alexsievert.com/argena/chandaria/chandarian-history/an-overall-history-of-chandaria.html#The_Age_of_Dominion" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Age of Dominion</a>. The Nexus was originally built at the beginning of the Age of Dominion under the oversight of Godrick Lansen. It became memorialized when it was rebuilt after the <a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="An Overall History Of Chandaria > The Age of Dominion" data-href="An Overall History Of Chandaria#The Age of Dominion" href="http://wiki.alexsievert.com/argena/chandaria/chandarian-history/an-overall-history-of-chandaria.html#The_Age_of_Dominion" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Sundering of the Nexus</a>. There is a statue of a bunch of hands holding up a depiction of the Great Wheel and a memorial plaque inside the new Nexus that has the names of all those who died in the attack.]]></description><link>http://wiki.alexsievert.com/argena/chandaria/nations/valdens/spellhaven.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Argena/Chandaria/Nations/Valdens/Spellhaven.md</guid><pubDate>Fri, 28 Feb 2025 01:06:13 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Valdens]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br>Capital City: Spellhaven<br>Spellhaven is the most technologically advanced city in Chandaria. Magic in this city is extremely commonplace, and used in nearly all facets of society. The city is in the center of the island, and has 8 roads, The Arcane Byways, leading out from the center, each one going to a town dedicated to one of the schools of magic.<br>
The Sanctum Arcana is the largest collection of knowledge and texts in Chandaria. It is very private and heavily guarded.]]></description><link>http://wiki.alexsievert.com/argena/chandaria/nations/valdens/valdens.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Argena/Chandaria/Nations/Valdens/Valdens.md</guid><pubDate>Mon, 22 Apr 2024 19:47:10 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[The Wildlands]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br>The Wildlands are the islands in the southwest of Chandaria. There is no overall governing body so there is no official capital city. The closest thing to one is the lawless pirate haven of Kraken Cove. This is on the north side of the large island, and it's rumored that the cove was hollowed out by a Kraken long ago. There still remain some Kraken worshippers in the city.]]></description><link>http://wiki.alexsievert.com/argena/chandaria/nations/wildlands/the-wildlands.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Argena/Chandaria/Nations/Wildlands/The Wildlands.md</guid><pubDate>Mon, 22 Jan 2024 00:40:52 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[The Clockwork Consortium]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br>The Clockwork Consortium is made up of the smartest inventors and tinkerers in all of <a data-href="Chandaria" href="http://wiki.alexsievert.com/argena/chandaria/chandaria.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Chandaria</a>. A majority of the members in the Consortium are gnomes and dwarves, but there are humans and elves that make up smaller sects of the constituents as well. The headquarters of the Clockwork Consortium are in <a data-href="Welbenwallow" href="http://wiki.alexsievert.com/argena/chandaria/nations/no'zaral/welbenwallow.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Welbenwallow</a> in the republic of <a data-href="No'zaral" href="http://wiki.alexsievert.com/argena/chandaria/nations/no'zaral/no'zaral.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">No'zaral</a>. The Consortium creates clockwork devices for whoever pays them the most money, or in rare times they will band together to do what the Master Tinkerer deems beneficial. ]]></description><link>http://wiki.alexsievert.com/argena/chandaria/organizations/the-clockwork-consortium.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Argena/Chandaria/Organizations/The Clockwork Consortium.md</guid><pubDate>Thu, 29 Feb 2024 18:06:06 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Chandaria]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br>The continent of Chandaria sits in the northeastern region of Argena (The Shattered Lands). Chandaria is home to many factions and kingdoms, and sports the whole gamut of climates. To the north there are snowy mountains and windswept tundra. To the south are tropical islands and fetid swamps. In the center of the continent is <a data-href="#The Eternal Scorch" href="http://wiki.alexsievert.com/about:blank#The_Eternal_Scorch" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">The Eternal Scorch</a>, a blistering hot desert with no more than small oases sprinkled throughout. Chandaria was home to multiple Ancient Archmages during <a data-href="The Great Dissension" href="http://wiki.alexsievert.com/argena/chandaria/chandarian-history/the-great-dissension.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">The Great Dissension</a> and still contains many Pre-Dissension era ruins.<br><br><br><a class="internal-link" data-href="The Kingdom of Falstor.md" href="http://wiki.alexsievert.com/argena/chandaria/nations/falstor/the-kingdom-of-falstor.html" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Falstor</a> encompasses the southeastern and northeastern peninsulas of the continent. Prior to the war with Stormion and the subsequent siege of the capital city, Falstor only occupied the southern peninsula, but the war for resources expanded their territory greatly. Falstor is ruled by the powerful King Offal. He conducts affairs leveraging both the economic and militaristic might of the kingdom. The capital city of the kingdom is the aptly named <a data-href="Falstor" href="http://wiki.alexsievert.com/argena/chandaria/nations/falstor/falstor.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Falstor</a>.<br><br><a data-href="The Larenthian Alliance" href="http://wiki.alexsievert.com/argena/chandaria/nations/larenthian-alliance/the-larenthian-alliance.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">The Larenthian Alliance</a> presides in the north central region of Chandaria, just above <a data-href="#The Eternal Scorch" href="http://wiki.alexsievert.com/about:blank#The_Eternal_Scorch" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">The Eternal Scorch</a>. It consists of multiple independent cities, united under a commercial federation. The alliance is lead by Chief Magnate Thedric Alfir from its capital city of <a data-href="Galvenport" href="http://wiki.alexsievert.com/argena/chandaria/nations/larenthian-alliance/provinces/galvenport.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Galvenport</a>. The Larenthian Federation is held together by Overseers. These government workers are distributed to each city and are tasked with ensuring the enforcement of Federal Laws. Besides these laws, each city is free to govern its denizens as it sees fit. Most of the cities in Larenthia are built around some sort of flourishing export economy, whether it's wine, metal, potions, or clockwork machines.<br><br><a data-href="The Wildlands" href="http://wiki.alexsievert.com/argena/chandaria/nations/wildlands/the-wildlands.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">The Wildlands</a> is a large expanse of independent islands southwest of the main continent. Official maps only have the large islands of the area mapped. There are tens if not hundreds of unmapped and potentially unexplored islands in the region. These unmapped islands are no larger than a few miles in each direction.<br>
Piracy and smuggling are very prevalent in The Wildlands, and compose the majority of the commerce and activity in the Wildlands. There are also stories of untold riches hidden on mystical islands in this area.<br>
Established continental nations have, in the past, attempted to "civilize" the islands to stop illegal smuggling in their cities that is mainly sourced from the Wildlands. These attempts have all been unsuccessful, since the most skilled naval crews and navigators lay down everything to protect the freedom of the Wildlands.<br><br><a data-href="Norlund" href="http://wiki.alexsievert.com/argena/chandaria/nations/norlund/norlund.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Norlund</a> is situated in the northwest extremes of the continent. Norlund lacks the large cities that populate a lot of the other nations of Chandaria. The harsh climate makes it hard to grow enough food to sustain large populations. The people of Norlund are considered by some to be "savages" or "barbarians" because they live in small clan villages and many lack the finer social graces of upper class society. The Kingdom's government consists of the heads of the most powerful clans in the land.<br>
Norlund's warrior culture has lead to some of the greatest warriors in the history of Chandaria have been born in Norlund and immortalized in myth. The government of Norlund puts considerable effort into keeping the nation mostly isolated from international activity. It's southern border, marked by the Champion's Range, is well-patrolled and fortified.<br><br><a data-href="No'zaral" href="http://wiki.alexsievert.com/argena/chandaria/nations/no'zaral/no'zaral.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">No'zaral</a> is a republic on the west coast of Chandaria. It is one of the most diverse nations on the continent, due to the general freedom that is given to its citizens. The Freeman's Assembly is the governing body of No'zaral, and consists of elected officials representing people of many different races. The nature of the republic has led to the different humanoid races forming political parties to elect representatives for their people.<br>
Other than social and political innovation, No'zaral also boasts a rather strong navy, due to its relative proximity to The Wildlands. The Clockwork Consortium, an organization of mostly Gnomish inventors has a strong presence in No'zaral, especially as it relates to the navy. The Clockwork Consortium is not bound to the republic, and has members all over Chandaria, doing work for whomever pays well, or whatever the leaders of the Consortium deem to be important. <br><br>The <a data-href="Atrisean Dynasty" href="http://wiki.alexsievert.com/argena/chandaria/nations/atrisean-dynasty/atrisean-dynasty.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Atrisean Dynasty</a>, despite its proximity to the republic of No'zaral, could not be further from it in social and political organization. The dynastic rulers of Atrisea, the Teinithra Clan, have elevated themselves to a status of almost lesser deities in the eyes of some of the most loyal citizens. The Teinithra Clan holds all of the governing power in the dynasty, and swiftly quells any source of rebellion within its borders. The Teinithras have been in power for a few hundred years, having usurped power from the Jelenneth family before them. There are families that have tried to take power from the Teinithra, but none have been successful.<br>
The Atrisean Dynasty also has a very powerful navy, but is more aggressive in terms of international relations, and worries the other nations of Chandaria.<br><br>The Island Nation of <a data-href="Valdens" href="http://wiki.alexsievert.com/argena/chandaria/nations/valdens/valdens.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Valdens</a> is a flourishing meritocracy. The nation is ruled by the Council of Eight, with the most powerful mage from each school of magic sitting on the council. Valdens is Chandaria's hub for arcane research and innovation, and most of the culture being entirely focused on magic. The Pillars of Arcanum, the laws regarding the practice of magic in Valdens, highlight that magic should only be used for the betterment of society, and the further pursuit of knowledge. Valdens has no standing army, but if they were to be forced to fight, they would be very capable of putting together a formidable fighting force.<br><br>The Kingdom of <a data-href="Rodigia" href="http://wiki.alexsievert.com/argena/chandaria/nations/rodigia/rodigia.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Rodigia</a> is a very mountainous region, but unlike the dwarves of Essaheim, the Rodigian people mastered living above the mountains, not beneath them. The Mountain King of Rodigia, rules over the nation's various villages and tribes fairly, and is very well liked and respected by all of his constituents.<br>
Rodigia is known for having a large population of giants that live there, who are known for being very territorial, and very stubborn fighters.<br>
The Rangers of Rodigia are an order of rangers that specialize in traversing the harsh mountainous environment that spans most of the region. They are very talented archers and also focus on maintaining the peace between the more brutish giants and the forces of nature.<br><br>The Eternal Scorch, the desert in the middle of Chandaria, has no overall governing body and little permanent settlement. The landscape is brutal and doesn't allow much of anything to grow, except around small oases. Roving nomadic tribes inhabit the areas that aren't these small oases.]]></description><link>http://wiki.alexsievert.com/argena/chandaria/chandaria.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Argena/Chandaria/Chandaria.md</guid><pubDate>Fri, 19 Jan 2024 07:08:56 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Games]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br>Games are a popular pastime for all manner of folk across <a data-href="Chandaria" href="http://wiki.alexsievert.com/argena/chandaria/chandaria.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Chandaria</a>. Games are played in taverns, castle keeps, and hovels alike throughout the land. The popularity of games has also led to the rise of gambling. Gambling often happens in taverns, but it can also happen in more private areas too. Gambling however, is not legal across all of <a data-href="Chandaria" href="http://wiki.alexsievert.com/argena/chandaria/chandaria.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Chandaria</a>, with areas such as <a data-href="Luminespore Hollow" href="http://wiki.alexsievert.com/argena/chandaria/nations/larenthian-alliance/provinces/luminespore-hollow.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Luminespore Hollow</a> in the <a class="internal-link" data-href="The Larenthian Alliance.md" href="http://wiki.alexsievert.com/argena/chandaria/nations/larenthian-alliance/the-larenthian-alliance.html" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Larenthian Alliance</a>, and <a data-href="Marrisburg" href="http://wiki.alexsievert.com/argena/chandaria/nations/falstor/marrisburg.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Marrisburg</a> in <a class="internal-link" data-href="The Kingdom of Falstor.md" href="http://wiki.alexsievert.com/argena/chandaria/nations/falstor/the-kingdom-of-falstor.html" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Falstor</a> outlawing gambling.<br><br>Common games across <a data-href="Chandaria" href="http://wiki.alexsievert.com/argena/chandaria/chandaria.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Chandaria</a> include <a data-href="#Fiendish Fortune" href="http://wiki.alexsievert.com/about:blank#Fiendish_Fortune" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Fiendish Fortune</a>, <a data-href="#3 Die Divination" href="http://wiki.alexsievert.com/about:blank#3_Die_Divination" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">3 Die Divination</a>, and <a data-href="#Scurvy Knave" href="http://wiki.alexsievert.com/about:blank#Scurvy_Knave" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Scurvy Knave</a>.<br><br>Fiendish Fortune is a card game that originated among the dwarves in the mines of <a data-href="Essaheim" href="http://wiki.alexsievert.com/argena/chandaria/nations/essaheim/essaheim.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Essaheim</a>. When playing the game, those who were very good at it were said to have struck a deal with a devil to have luck that rivalled that of <a data-href="Lucite" href="http://wiki.alexsievert.com/argena/gods/lucite.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Lucite</a>.<br>
Fiendish Fortune involves both players placing down an equal ante. Once the antes are placed, each player draws three cards. This is simulated by the player rolling 3d6. The ranking of hands is as follows:<br>
<br>Three of a kind (Highest)
<br>Straight
<br>Flush (All even or all odd)
<br>Pair
<br>High Card (Lowest)<br>
The player can place into the pot an additional amount of money equal to their ante to redraw (reroll) one card. The player with the higher hand wins all the money in the pot.
<br><br>This game originated in the halls of the Grand Halls of <a class="internal-link" data-href="Valdens.md" href="http://wiki.alexsievert.com/argena/chandaria/nations/valdens/valdens.html" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Spellhaven</a>. It actually originated as an exercise in the Divination schools to teach students how to do simple prediction. Students then took the game and began spreading it on the streets in cities across <a data-href="Chandaria" href="http://wiki.alexsievert.com/argena/chandaria/chandaria.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Chandaria</a>, introducing the gambling aspect of the game.<br>
The player bets any amount, chooses a number between 1 and 6. The dealer then rolls 3d6. If one die matches the player's number, they get their money back plus an equal amount. If two dice match the player's number, they get their money back plus double the amount. If three dice match the player's number, they get their money back plus triple the amount. And if none of the dice match, the dealer keeps the player's money.<br><br>Scurvy Knave isn't as popular as the other two games, and is usually only played in gambling houses and casinos. It comes from the royal courts of <a data-href="No'zaral" href="http://wiki.alexsievert.com/argena/chandaria/nations/no'zaral/no'zaral.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">No'zaral</a>. The term "Scurvy Knave" referred to the flamboyant jesters who would challenge people in this game and take all of their money.<br>
Scurvy Knave is a card game played with a 52 card deck. It involves a dealer and between 1 and 4 players. The game is played exactly like real-life <a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="https://www.blackjackapprenticeship.com/how-to-play-blackjack/" rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link" href="https://www.blackjackapprenticeship.com/how-to-play-blackjack/" target="_blank">Blackjack</a>. ]]></description><link>http://wiki.alexsievert.com/argena/chandaria/games.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Argena/Chandaria/Games.md</guid><pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 02:57:19 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Enulon]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br>Enulon is the largest and oldest continent on Argena. It's located in the western hemisphere and spans most of the region from north to south. It has an extremely diverse landscape of sweeping plains, towering mountain ranges, and fertile river valleys. Eastern Enulon is much more developed than the west, as the shortest sea routes to the other continents are from the Eastern coast.<br>Enulon is thought to be the oldest continent because of the works of the First Builders. This mysterious race of people constructed massive stone structures. These ruins are scattered across the entire continent, and suggest that this civilization had advanced knowledge of engineering. What confuses many scholars is that it seems as though the civilization must have had some sort of magical ability to be able to construct these buildings because they are simply to large and too advanced to be made simply by hand. However, these structures were ruined and the First Builders were long gone by the time that the earliest records of Tilarien were written. These records were written around 8,000 years Pre-Dissension. Thus, the First Builders would have had no way to use magic since mortals weren't granted spellcasting until the Great Dissension. While this is by no means what Enulon is most known for, it is one of Argena's most defining historical events.<br>Modern Enulon is known as a melting pot of cultures. Descendants from ancient empires and newer settlers coexist in large cities and small villages all across the continent. Economically, Enulon is known as a trading powerhouse simply due to the diverse goods that it has access to.<br><br><br>The Eastern Concord is the largest intercontinental traders. ]]></description><link>http://wiki.alexsievert.com/argena/enulon/enulon.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Argena/Enulon/Enulon.md</guid><pubDate>Fri, 14 Mar 2025 18:31:44 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Amphinor]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br>Chaotic Neutral god of the sea. His domain is in Limbo. His symbol is a trident with a serpent coiled up the handle.]]></description><link>http://wiki.alexsievert.com/argena/gods/amphinor.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Argena/Gods/Amphinor.md</guid><pubDate>Tue, 16 Jul 2024 21:53:49 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Annam]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br>Lawful Neutral god of Giants. He lives in exile in the Outlands. His symbol is a pair of hands with their wrists together and the fingers pointing down.]]></description><link>http://wiki.alexsievert.com/argena/gods/annam.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Argena/Gods/Annam.md</guid><pubDate>Tue, 16 Jul 2024 21:55:11 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Arbitros]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br>Lawful Good god of justice. He inhabits the plane of Mount Celestia. His symbol is a balanced scale sitting atop a sideways sword.]]></description><link>http://wiki.alexsievert.com/argena/gods/arbitros.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Argena/Gods/Arbitros.md</guid><pubDate>Tue, 16 Jul 2024 21:58:24 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Artanor]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br>Neutral Evil god of darkness and shadows. He rules over one of the layers of Hades. His symbol is a golden circle with a horizontal line stricken through it.]]></description><link>http://wiki.alexsievert.com/argena/gods/artanor.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Argena/Gods/Artanor.md</guid><pubDate>Tue, 16 Jul 2024 21:59:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Asmodeus]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br>Lawful Evil god of tyranny who inhabits Nessus, the lowest level of the Nine Hells. His symbol is three triangles arranged into a larger, long triangle pointed downwards.]]></description><link>http://wiki.alexsievert.com/argena/gods/asmodeus.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Argena/Gods/Asmodeus.md</guid><pubDate>Tue, 16 Jul 2024 22:01:06 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Balinor]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br>Neutral Good god of beasts and the hunt. He lives in the Beastlands. His symbol is a stag's head in front of a crescent moon.]]></description><link>http://wiki.alexsievert.com/argena/gods/balinor.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Argena/Gods/Balinor.md</guid><pubDate>Tue, 16 Jul 2024 22:04:49 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Chaos]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br>Chaotic Evil god of madness. He rules over most of Limbo. His symbol is an eye, with a spiral for the iris. The spiral has cracks through it from the center.]]></description><link>http://wiki.alexsievert.com/argena/gods/chaos.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Argena/Gods/Chaos.md</guid><pubDate>Tue, 16 Jul 2024 22:08:19 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Cielia]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br>Neutral Good goddess of agriculture. Her domain is among the fields of Elysium. Her symbol is a bundle of wheat surrounded by a circular vine with blooming flowers along it.]]></description><link>http://wiki.alexsievert.com/argena/gods/cielia.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Argena/Gods/Cielia.md</guid><pubDate>Tue, 16 Jul 2024 22:12:06 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Erathis]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br>Lawful Neutral goddess of knowledge. She rules over her domain in Arcadia. Her symbol is an open book with a quill pen writing in it.]]></description><link>http://wiki.alexsievert.com/argena/gods/erathis.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Argena/Gods/Erathis.md</guid><pubDate>Tue, 16 Jul 2024 22:15:10 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Eurus]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br>Chaotic Evil god of storms. He inhabits Pandemonium. ]]></description><link>http://wiki.alexsievert.com/argena/gods/eurus.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Argena/Gods/Eurus.md</guid><pubDate>Tue, 16 Jul 2024 22:15:14 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Genesis]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br>Neutral Good goddess of creation. She inhabits the Progenitor's Palace in the Outlands.]]></description><link>http://wiki.alexsievert.com/argena/gods/genesis.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Argena/Gods/Genesis.md</guid><pubDate>Sat, 27 Jan 2024 19:37:21 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Gruumsh]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br>Chaotic Evil god of destruction. He lords over Acheron.]]></description><link>http://wiki.alexsievert.com/argena/gods/gruumsh.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Argena/Gods/Gruumsh.md</guid><pubDate>Sat, 27 Jan 2024 19:37:23 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Harmonia]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br>Chaotic Good goddess of Magic and the Arts. She lives on Arborea.]]></description><link>http://wiki.alexsievert.com/argena/gods/harmonia.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Argena/Gods/Harmonia.md</guid><pubDate>Sat, 27 Jan 2024 19:37:27 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Libai]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br>Lawful Good goddess of life who inhabits the twin paradises of Bytopia.]]></description><link>http://wiki.alexsievert.com/argena/gods/libai.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Argena/Gods/Libai.md</guid><pubDate>Sat, 27 Jan 2024 03:07:55 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Lolth]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br>Chaotic Evil goddess of spiders and lies. She lives amongst the infinite levels of The Abyss]]></description><link>http://wiki.alexsievert.com/argena/gods/lolth.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Argena/Gods/Lolth.md</guid><pubDate>Sat, 27 Jan 2024 19:37:35 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Lucite]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br>Chaotic Good goddess of fortune and luck. She lives on Ysgard.]]></description><link>http://wiki.alexsievert.com/argena/gods/lucite.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Argena/Gods/Lucite.md</guid><pubDate>Sat, 27 Jan 2024 19:37:39 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Maglubiyet]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br>Lawful Evil god of Goblinkind. His domain is in Acheron, eternally fighting against Gruumsh.]]></description><link>http://wiki.alexsievert.com/argena/gods/maglubiyet.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Argena/Gods/Maglubiyet.md</guid><pubDate>Tue, 09 Jul 2024 22:15:58 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Mortessa]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br>True Neutral goddess of death. She presides over the Scales of Life in the Outlands.<br>People who follow the teachings of Mortessa don't necessarily follow a particular alignment. Mortessa herself is True Neutral because she decides where each soul goes to spend the afterlife. Her followers are not trying to emulate her being, they are instead focused on guiding those who seek a certain lot in the afterlife. Priests of Mortessa, the most powerful of which are known as Raven Kings and Queens, have their own ideas of alignment, some may be lawful good while others might be chaotic evil. The unifying idea between all of the priests is that they will offer guidance to those who seek to live their life in a certain alignment.<br>
In society, it is those in the service of Mortessa that handle funeral rites and ensure that the dead get the proper treatment so that their souls may depart peacefully and easily to the Scales of Life and then to whichever outer plane Mortessa sees fit. It is a common belief that if the dead aren't treated to proper funeral rites that their souls might become lost on the way to the Outlands and they may end up as wandering spirits or ghosts.]]></description><link>http://wiki.alexsievert.com/argena/gods/mortessa.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Argena/Gods/Mortessa.md</guid><pubDate>Mon, 26 Feb 2024 19:41:47 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Naivara]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br>Chaotic Good goddess of the Moon who lives on Ysgard.]]></description><link>http://wiki.alexsievert.com/argena/gods/naivara.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Argena/Gods/Naivara.md</guid><pubDate>Sat, 27 Jan 2024 19:37:42 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Pholtus]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br>Lawful Good god of light and law. He inhabits Mount Celestia.]]></description><link>http://wiki.alexsievert.com/argena/gods/pholtus.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Argena/Gods/Pholtus.md</guid><pubDate>Sat, 27 Jan 2024 19:37:45 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Reicha]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br>True Neutral Goddess of wealth and prosperity. Her domain is the Planar Bank in the Outlands.]]></description><link>http://wiki.alexsievert.com/argena/gods/reicha.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Argena/Gods/Reicha.md</guid><pubDate>Sat, 27 Jan 2024 19:37:49 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Terra]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br>True Neutral goddess of nature and the wilderness. She inhabits the Beastlands.]]></description><link>http://wiki.alexsievert.com/argena/gods/terra.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Argena/Gods/Terra.md</guid><pubDate>Sat, 27 Jan 2024 19:37:54 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[The Blood Chief]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br>Chaotic Evil god of war and violence. He lives in The Abyss.]]></description><link>http://wiki.alexsievert.com/argena/gods/the-blood-chief.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Argena/Gods/The Blood Chief.md</guid><pubDate>Sat, 27 Jan 2024 18:57:16 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Tiamat]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br>Lawful Evil goddess of greed and vengeance. Her domain is among Avernus, the first layer of the Nine Hells.]]></description><link>http://wiki.alexsievert.com/argena/gods/tiamat.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Argena/Gods/Tiamat.md</guid><pubDate>Sat, 27 Jan 2024 19:38:05 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Valos]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br>Chaotic Good god of the sun. He lives on the plane of Arborea.]]></description><link>http://wiki.alexsievert.com/argena/gods/valos.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Argena/Gods/Valos.md</guid><pubDate>Sat, 27 Jan 2024 19:37:59 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Vecna]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br>Neutral Evil god of evil secrets. He has domains on both Hades and Pandemonium.]]></description><link>http://wiki.alexsievert.com/argena/gods/vecna.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Argena/Gods/Vecna.md</guid><pubDate>Sat, 27 Jan 2024 19:38:09 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Yurk]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br>Lawful Evil god of the underdark. He lives on Gehenna.]]></description><link>http://wiki.alexsievert.com/argena/gods/yurk.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Argena/Gods/Yurk.md</guid><pubDate>Sat, 27 Jan 2024 02:59:20 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Tilarien]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br>Tilarien is a medium-sized continent in the southeastern hemisphere of Argena. Its name descends from the ancient elves that inhabited it in the Pre-Dissension era. The ancient elves of Tilarien kept very detailed records of the continent's history, so much more of its past is known than the other continents.<br>Modern Tilarien is known as the prime exporter of artisan goods and a land full of high society, highly-stratified nations. The craftsmen of Tilarien are renowned for their integration of magic and craftwork. The land itself is steeped in innate magic that is said to leak in from the Feywild.]]></description><link>http://wiki.alexsievert.com/argena/tilarien/tilarien.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Argena/Tilarien/Tilarien.md</guid><pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2025 20:28:24 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Caelum Insula]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br>The archipelago of Caelum Insula floats over the great waves of the Azure Expanse, drifting through the clouds between Chandaria and Enulon. The islands themselves are as old as Argena itself, and have deep connections to the Gods.<br>Caelum Insula is also called the Cradle of Life because it's thought to have been where the Gods experimented when creating life. The few that have been to the islands claim to have seen bizarre monsters and aberrations.<br>The reason so few people have been to Caelum Insula is because it's impossible to determine where the archipelago will be at a given time over the millions of miles of ocean between Chandaria and Enulon. Most of the travel to Caelum Insula these days is via teleportation routes that were established long ago.<br><br>Caelum Insula also holds historical significance as the place where the Scourge began. During the Great Dissension, Caelum Insula was a highly contested area because of its undetectability. Whichever side controlled Caelum Insula had an unlocatable base of operations on the Material Plane.<br>The Gods of the Lower Planes claimed the islands for themselves at the beginning of the Great Dissension and held it for the majority of the war. They used it as a staging grounds for their forces on the Material Plane. Once the forces of the Upper Planes realized that the Lower Deities were staging from the islands, they began searching. They searched for years without finding anything. As Anteitic ideologies grew stronger and reached a tipping point, Kadarin, an Ancient Archmage in the service of the Lower Deities assisted the Archmages of the Upper Deities in locating the Islands. With that, the Upper Deities planned their assault.<br>As the battle got underway and the two sides clashed in combat, the mages of both sides suddenly turned, firing upon both sides' armies. With the element of surprise, the Anteity League easily forced both sides to retreat, claiming Caelum Insula for themselves. This event is known as the Divine Betrayal, and marks the beginning of the Scourge.]]></description><link>http://wiki.alexsievert.com/argena/caelum-insula.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Argena/Caelum Insula.md</guid><pubDate>Tue, 04 Jun 2024 03:54:43 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Calendar]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br>Holiday: Deepwinter<br>
Glanix<br>
Hemlia<br>
Holiday: The Bloom<br>
Verna<br>
Pluvis<br>
Florum<br>
Holiday: Soltide<br>
Aestia<br>
Calo<br>
Ignus<br>
Holiday: The Harvest Moon<br>
Otun<br>
Messime<br>
Planimor<br>
Holiday: Nocturn<br>
Friga]]></description><link>http://wiki.alexsievert.com/argena/calendar.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Argena/Calendar.md</guid><pubDate>Fri, 19 Jan 2024 07:08:52 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Gods and Mythos]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br><br>
<br><a data-href="Lucite" href="http://wiki.alexsievert.com/argena/gods/lucite.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Lucite</a> - Goddess of fortune and luck
<br><a data-href="Pholtus" href="http://wiki.alexsievert.com/argena/gods/pholtus.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Pholtus</a> - God of light and law
<br><a data-href="Erathis" href="http://wiki.alexsievert.com/argena/gods/erathis.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Erathis</a> - Goddess of knowledge
<br><a data-href="Reicha" href="http://wiki.alexsievert.com/argena/gods/reicha.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Reicha</a> - Goddess of wealth and prosperity
<br><a data-href="Balinor" href="http://wiki.alexsievert.com/argena/gods/balinor.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Balinor</a> - God of beasts and the hunts
<br><a data-href="Valos" href="http://wiki.alexsievert.com/argena/gods/valos.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Valos</a> - God of the Sun
<br><a data-href="Mortessa" href="http://wiki.alexsievert.com/argena/gods/mortessa.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Mortessa</a> - Goddess of Death
<br><a data-href="Libai" href="http://wiki.alexsievert.com/argena/gods/libai.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Libai</a>  Goddess of Life 
<br><a data-href="Cielia" href="http://wiki.alexsievert.com/argena/gods/cielia.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Cielia</a> - Goddess of Agriculture
<br><a data-href="Asmodeus" href="http://wiki.alexsievert.com/argena/gods/asmodeus.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Asmodeus</a> - God of Tyranny
<br><a data-href="Tiamat" href="http://wiki.alexsievert.com/argena/gods/tiamat.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Tiamat</a> - Goddess of Greed and Vengeance
<br><a data-href="Lolth" href="http://wiki.alexsievert.com/argena/gods/lolth.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Lolth</a> - Goddess of Spiders and Lies
<br><a data-href="Arbitros" href="http://wiki.alexsievert.com/argena/gods/arbitros.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Arbitros</a> - God of Justice
<br><a data-href="The Blood Chief" href="http://wiki.alexsievert.com/argena/gods/the-blood-chief.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">The Blood Chief</a> - God of War and Violence
<br><a data-href="Harmonia" href="http://wiki.alexsievert.com/argena/gods/harmonia.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Harmonia</a> - Goddess of Magic and the Arts
<br><a data-href="Gruumsh" href="http://wiki.alexsievert.com/argena/gods/gruumsh.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Gruumsh</a> - God of Destruction
<br><a data-href="Eurus" href="http://wiki.alexsievert.com/argena/gods/eurus.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Eurus</a> - God of Storms
<br><a data-href="Terra" href="http://wiki.alexsievert.com/argena/gods/terra.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Terra</a> - Goddess of Nature and the Wilderness
<br><a data-href="Amphinor" href="http://wiki.alexsievert.com/argena/gods/amphinor.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Amphinor</a> - God of the Sea
<br><a data-href="Genesis" href="http://wiki.alexsievert.com/argena/gods/genesis.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Genesis</a> - Goddess of Creation
<br><a data-href="Naivara" href="http://wiki.alexsievert.com/argena/gods/naivara.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Naivara</a> - Goddess of the Moon
<br><a data-href="Chaos" href="http://wiki.alexsievert.com/argena/gods/chaos.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Chaos</a> - God of Madness
<br><a data-href="Yurk" href="http://wiki.alexsievert.com/argena/gods/yurk.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Yurk</a> - God of the Underdark
<br><a data-href="Vecna" href="http://wiki.alexsievert.com/argena/gods/vecna.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Vecna</a> - God of Evil Secrets
<br><a data-href="Artanor" href="http://wiki.alexsievert.com/argena/gods/artanor.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Artanor</a> - God of Darkness and Shadows
<br><a data-href="Annam" href="http://wiki.alexsievert.com/argena/gods/annam.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Annam</a> - God of Giants
<br><a data-href="Maglubiyet" href="http://wiki.alexsievert.com/argena/gods/maglubiyet.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Maglubiyet</a> - God of Goblinkind
<br><br><br>No one knows what came before the gods or where the gods even came from, but the gods are said to be the first beings to harness the primordial forces of the multiverse into something tangible. Genesis and Gruumsh were the first two gods to begin the shaping of worlds. It began as a competition between the two, with Genesis building entire worlds, planes of existence, just for Gruumsh to destroy them and start the process anew. Other gods joined Genesis in creating, adding more complexity to the worlds. Harmonia infused the multiverse with some of her raw magical power, and Terra created the first non-divine beings. These beings are incomprehensible to people now, their primitiveness and alienness would break the mind of anyone today. The gods became especially focused on the material plane, which they all agreed was common ground for experimentation. This world became so complex that Gruumsh was no longer able to destroy it completely, which he soon gave up trying to do and began plotting something else.<br>Valos and Artanor couldn't agree on whether the world should be bathed in light or shrouded in darkness, so they compromised and agreed that the world would alternate between darkness and light. Artanor got lonely in the dark though, so he asked his wife Naivara to accompany the darkness whenever it spread across the world, thus why the moon always accompanies the night.<br>Eventually the gods got bored of messing around with the material plane, leaving it in a state that is believed to be similar to the earliest tales tell. They began creating their own domains far removed from the material plane (the outer planes).<br><br>The primitive material plane was pretty boring. All of the creatures just sort of existed without really doing much. Being mostly powerless, these creatures were bent to the will of the gods. Harmonia was not a fan of this, and decided to do something to change it. Harmonia sacrificed a part of her very essence in an event now known as the Fracture, which in turn diffused throughout the multiverse, creating a well of raw magical power that could be drawn on by other creatures. Dragons were the first creatures to gain a sufficient mastery of drawing on the well of raw magic. However, it wouldn't be until the Great Dissension that the idea of the weave was created and humanoids learned to draw from its power.<br>Most of the gods weren't happy that others were able to tap into magical power, as it could be used to rebel against the gods. Even so, Harmonia's sacrifice was irreversible, and the gods were unable to get rid of the magic in the multiverse.<br>As a consequence, Harmonia was imprisoned in Carceri for 10,000 years.<br><br>After the Fracture, the Gods became very concerned about the non-divine beings rising up against them. Mortessa put forth the idea that all non-divine beings should be destined to die eventually, with their physical body being left behind and their soul departing to live out its days on one of the outer planes, usually one that follows the creature's alignment. The idea of death was very foreign to the gods, as they were immortal and couldn't fathom the idea of ceasing to exist. Mortessa took it upon herself to be the custodian of death, making sure that all creatures were destined to die at some point. A creature's death from old age was determined when they were born, but their life could be cut short, and Mortessa would come to determine where their soul was bound to go. On very rare and sometimes legendary occasions, Mortessa decides that one's soul is not yet ready to depart for the outer planes, and spares beings from death in an act of mercy.<br><br>Once the multiverse had become so complex that Gruumsh could no longer destroy it, he got increasingly jealous and bored. He and his son, The Blood Chief, decided to enlist Chaos to help them incite madness across the realms and spread death. They went throughout the material plane, slaughtering people and holding onto their souls, preventing them from departing to the outer planes. They put these captured souls into their own vessels, called Orcs, who were crafted to their liking. Once a soul was put into the Orc, Chaos imbued it with a sense of madness, giving all Orcs an ever-hungry bloodlust. Eventually, the gods of the good planes were able to muster enough power to halt their march across the material plane. By this point however, Gruumsh, The Blood Chief, and Chaos had amassed enough souls that they had a very influential bargaining chip, so the gods made a deal: Gruumsh and the Blood Chief were allowed to create their own plane, Acheron, far away from the domain of the existing planes. In return, Gruumsh and the Blood Chief released the souls they had collected to the outer planes. Because Acheron exists outside of the domain of Mortessa, endless battle ensues, with the slain indefinitely being resurrected to fight again.<br>Chaos however, didn't want to go to Acheron, and as part of the ultimatum was instead banished to Carceri.<br><br>Chaos was imprisoned on Carceri as a consequence of the First Blood War. It was during this banishment that The Blood Chief tasked Chaos with assisting in the creation of many of the demons that inhabit The Abyss. The Blood Chief told him that only once he had created an army to rival his father's on Acheron would he be set free. Chaos, a primordial himself, didn't like being commanded by the son of another, and he set about escaping Limbo. No one knows how he did it, but it is said that one day, he simply vanished from the plane. Some say that the passage that he used can still be used by those stuck on the plane today. After escaping Carceri, Chaos found himself without a true domain of his own. It was not his nature to rule over anything with any sort of order. Chaos traveled to the edge of the multiverse, exploring the depths of the Astral Plane. This is known as the Voyage of Chaos. He traveled far beyond the known bounds of the Astral Plane, reaching an area where there was no sense of order or cohesiveness at all. It was perfect. Here, leftover material from the creation of other planes, elemental debris, and random force all collided in a grand cacophony. Chaos wanted to savor this unruliness, so he set about containing it for himself. He used his primordial power to fashion borders to a large expanse of the nothingness. Eventually, this area became separated enough from the Astral Plane that it became its own Outer Plane. This is how Limbo came to be, with Chaos being the lord over it.<br><br>After the First Blood War, and the concessions that were made because of it, The Blood Chief was one of the most powerful deities in the multiverse. He wasn't a primordial, so he didn't possess as much inherent power as his father, Gruumsh, but he had garnered just as much respect and reverence. He spent some time ruling over Acheron with his father, but one can only watch goblins and orcs slaughter each other for so long, and he also wanted to make an even greater name for himself. He began by creating an army under his father's nose on Acheron. It was in the creation of this army, that The Blood Chief first began experimenting with creating his own sentient creatures. Said to be the very first demons, these creatures were mixed in with the usual inhabitants of Acheron to create a formidable army. The Blood Chief's army marched on Malus, Gruumsh's Palace, in a show of power against Gruumsh. However, Gruumsh's honor guard made quick work of this army in a brutal slaughter known as the Bloodbath of Malus. Gruumsh was emotionally devastated by his son's treachery. Gruumsh, the malicious tyrant that he is, saw simple banishment unfit for his son, so he cast him and all of his cruel creations into The Abyss. This "Abyss" had long sat among the lower planes. No one, including the gods, know how it came to be, but it is said to be infinitely deep and impossible to navigate. The Blood Chief came to call The Abyss home. Here he was free to create as many of his demonic monsters as he wanted. Amongst the infinite layers of The Abyss, The Blood Chief continued to raise his army anew, plotting, always plotting.<br>]]></description><link>http://wiki.alexsievert.com/argena/gods-and-mythos.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Argena/Gods and Mythos.md</guid><pubDate>Mon, 10 Feb 2025 03:26:34 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Harmonium]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br>Harmonium was discovered during the Arcane Resurgence. It created such a boom for arcane technologies that it became the most valuable resource in the world. The crystal is thought to be solid remnants of Harmonia's sacrifice during the <a class="internal-link" data-href="Gods and Mythos" href="http://wiki.alexsievert.com/argena/gods-and-mythos.html" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Fracture</a>, deposited across the Material Plane during the creation of the planes.<br>Harmonium crystals have many uses that have been discovered. One use is as a substitution for material spell components. Harmonium is mined in its raw form, and in this form, it acts as double its value as a spell component. However, the spell also has a chance of failing and causing a wild magic surge. The mages of the Arcane Resurgence found a way to refine Harmonium into a more stable state. Through magical smithing, they were able to reduce the potency of the crystal in order to make it more stable. It takes more refined Harmonium to substitute as spell components, but it has no chance of failure.<br>Another use for Harmonium is in magical crafting. The Kainomancers quickly discovered that using Harmonium crystals could greatly increase the speed of crafting magic items. This made the mineral even more valuable.<br>In the modern day, Harmonium is very rare. Very little is found in the wild anymore, and most is stockpiled by powerful governments. It is thought that Spellhaven has the largest reserve of Harmonium in Chandaria.]]></description><link>http://wiki.alexsievert.com/argena/harmonium.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Argena/Harmonium.md</guid><pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 01:49:34 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>